I'm sorry, I didn't feel like talking to you guys.
It's nothing personal, kid.
I just wanted to play the game.
What are you gonna do?
What are you gonna do about it?
Alright, what was I doing last time?
Um... Oh yeah, right!
We had a list.
We need to make a windmill on top of the house!
This needs your full attention!
Got it!
The path outside the house isn't complete yet.
You forgot the other side of the house.
Get on it!
Mossy stones are the future, kid.
Nice.
We need to kidnap the hotel, so go find one.
That's on the to-do list.
Money not spent is money saved.
Very wise words.
Bissm skib-skib-i-slo-pon-mack-like-less-plow.
Very good.
I'm sorry!
I couldn't resist!
This is the fake list!
This is the real one!
Hahahaha!
Operation make assembly for andesite casing!
Deploy andesite alloy on stripped wood!
Ah, isn't that glorious?
Strip wood with deployer and axe!
Mix andesite and sink iron nuggets for andesite alloy.
I gotta be honest, I'm just reading this out loud.
I have no idea what he means.
I don't understand these words.
Andesite made from mixing cobblestone and diorite.
We need...
More than five mixers.
Basins, depots, deployers.
We need over a hundred belts, spinny rods, power source to power all of it.
Do not get distracted.
You will do this...
Now.
Let's do it!
I'm gonna take this with me.
So I don't forget.
I couldn't resist messing with you guys a little.
Ahhhh, okay.
Um...
Wait, what was I doing?
Let me actually read this and try and understand what I wrote.
Oh yeah, right!
So we gotta...
Yeah.
We gotta get all the mixers and stuff.
Let's focus on that first.
Also, the music is weirdly loud.
Isn't it?
Or is that just me?
Um...
How many...
I think I only have one mixer right now.
We need a whisk.
Oh!
That's why I took this out.
Makes sense.
Uh, did I go make some of these sheets?
I freaking did.
Uh...
I wonder if there's a way to take this without putting something back.
Hold on, I need to investigate.
Let's say I do this, right?
And I wanna take them while I have something in my hand.
Maybe I control click?
Shift click?
No?
I don't know.
It's impossible.
You can't do it.
I guess you can empty your hand first.
Yeah, actually.
You just go like this...
And pick it up.
Genius.
Unbelievable.
Okay, so now we have this.
We can make...
Mixers.
No.
Whisks.
And let's say...
Hmm...
Let's make...
Four.
No, five.
Stick to the rules.
We have five whisks now.
And to make a mixer...
We need andesite casings and cogwheel.
Okay.
I think I have that.
Or maybe not.
But I can turn these into smaller ones?
Wait, I didn't actually take that.
Let me see here if I remember.
Oh no, maybe I can't.
Oh!
But I can make big ones out of small ones.
Right.
I can't make smaller ones out of big ones.
That's too bad.
Shafts and oak planks.
I think I have a lot of shafts.
Yeah, I have 25 shafts.
And to make shafts, it's pretty easy, right?
Yeah.
Let's actually make a couple more.
Fifty-seven shanks of meat.
And 19 alloys left.
That means we are gonna need to go ahead and grab some...
...alloys.
Which I don't have.
Even though I seem to remember doing this last time.
But okay, maybe I'm just imagining things.
We may have to go make some more...
...andesite alloy right now.
Let's do a little bit more of this.
Dude, I love the sound of the spinny rods.
They make me happy.
How many did I get?
Sixteen.
Times the casings.
Good.
But that's not everything.
We also need the little cock wheels.
And for that, we just need wood.
Let's just make 27.
Uh...
Yes.
I'll make 27.
You can't stop me.
Okay.
Now mixers.
Let's make four.
Because we already have one outside.
Ah, shit.
No, it's fine.
Make five.
There you go.
Five mixers.
Done.
Let's review.
Basins and depots.
Okay.
Oh, it's just alloys.
Got it.
So we should focus on alloys right now.
Nuggets and andesites.
But it can also be iron nuggets.
Let's cook this.
In fact, I'm just gonna blast it real quick.
Don't care.
These belts, we don't need them just yet.
But very soon we'll need them.
This is a crazy contraption we have with us here.
This goes here.
Anything I don't need.
Maybe I don't need this right now.
This I need.
I don't need this contraption.
Let me put that in the corner so I don't forget.
Like that.
Or we put the specialized stuff in here.
The other create box.
I like that actually.
Okay.
And now we need andesite.
Which we have here.
I think.
Or it's maybe in my toolbox.
Yes it is.
How glorious is that?
And then we need the little nuggets.
Sink nuggets.
And this should be done now.
We can turn these into nuggets.
And now we make alloy.
35 alloys!
Just like that.
Basin.
There we go.
One, two, three, four, five.
Five basins.
Then we need depots.
Oh my god, it's easy.
We got five of those now.
Let's review.
Deployers we have?
No.
Yes, we have plenty of deployers.
Then we need a lot of belts.
Spinny rods.
Power source to power all of it.
Okay.
I would say the spinning rods is not quite there yet.
46.
We need more.
Which means we need more alloy.
Which means we need some of this stuff here.
Which I don't have.
Ah, man.
I really gotta go get some...
Sink?
That's like the one bottleneck right now.
Well, shit.
Guess I'll go do that.
Operation get sink.
Uh...
Should I bring my...
Mining contraption?
We have this.
Hmm.
I may actually...
Use that.
No.
Let's keep it simple right now.
It's too much work to set up.
I just need some sink real quick, you know?
It's not a...
Crazy adventure here.
Quick five-minute adventure.
In and out.
Or whatever it is.
They say.
In fact, I think I saw some on the way there.
When we dug last time.
In fact, I see some right now.
Nope.
That's just greenery.
Aha!
Found some.
Oh, I should have brought more torches.
Just realized.
But I can make some, right?
Can't.
Okay, let's get some coal real quick.
I have wood, so that's good.
He's coming.
Actually, I don't mind killing these guys.
I'm almost 30.
I think it's time to enchant another pickaxe, actually.
Oh my god, it's plentiful!
Let's get some coal.
Actually, iron is also good.
Sink and iron.
All I want.
Thank you.
16.
Uh, that's only gonna make 16 torches.
No.
There's more coming out.
I forgot my shield.
Dude, I am razor focused today.
This factory is gonna happen today.
I'm actually so excited about it.
I feel like it's all been building up to this, you know?
And it all stems from me wanting to get the andesite floor.
That's been the whole starting point.
Of this little adventure.
Man, this cave is actually insane.
It is so big.
Wait, I don't have any room?
Oh my god.
I honestly think we have enough.
Well, let's just get a little extra.
Just to be on the safe side.
And you get so much sink, actually, from mining this.
Compared to iron.
I think it's like multiplied.
38.
Yeah.
I'm good.
In fact, we're gonna blast this together with the iron.
Ultimate blasting.
I mean, look at this.
I was already down there, look.
I dropped some sink.
Nothing better than using the last cobblestone you have.
To clear up the inventory and get out of a hole.
That's one of the few joys.
In life.
Ah, who am I kidding?
There's a lot of joys in life.
It's one of many.
Let's just say that.
What's up, cow?
Oh!
I didn't mean to do that.
I was gonna pet you.
Instead I hit you.
I wonder if there's a way to pet them, actually.
Can I not just gently interact with them instead of punching them?
She's kinda evil.
Um...
Yeah, let's just go blast it, actually.
This is faster.
Uh...
Let's put the stuff in first.
This is the rule.
Anything else I wanna blast?
I'll try blasting this.
Who knows?
This should produce like 200 nuggets.
At least.
And it's done.
I'm gonna cover that up.
This is also the rule.
Grab it.
Jump.
Remove.
Good.
Damn, that's a lot.
I forgot what I was making though.
Oh yeah, andesite alloy.
But I can't.
Cause I need andesites.
Where did this?
And that.
Um...
Andesites.
That's in my box.
Oh my...
Dude, we're gonna make so much.
64!
We need more.
Holy shit!
Oh, I don't actually have that much.
I need more diorite so I can turn it into andesite.
I need diorite and cobblestone for that.
Did I leave some behind over here?
I feel like I had more.
Oh, we also have this.
And that.
I'm actually gonna mine this real quick.
Ah, wait a second.
We can actually blast this, right?
What's this called?
Copper ore?
Uh...
No, wait.
Copper...
Bar?
Ayy!
Look at that!
Direct blasting.
Um...
In you go.
And also this.
Lava.
And while that's doing that, I'm gonna go craft some real quick.
Oh, I didn't get the, uh, alloy.
I mean, andesite.
In fact, remove that.
Look at this!
Wonderful.
It should be done now.
Yep.
I'm just gonna grab it.
Fuck the rules.
They're made to be broken.
Okay.
So, obviously, right now, the bottleneck is andesite.
Or...
Diorite.
Both are kinda important right now.
This coal needs to go...
In one of these.
No, actually, that's away since we have blasting now.
I should just put it in here.
Maybe make some torches out of it, actually.
53.
That's perfect.
I don't need this or that now, or that.
We can make a couple more shafts.
That's why I did this.
There.
Two full stacks of shafts should be good enough.
Now, belts are coming.
There we go.
We don't need these rails right now.
That's equipment.
Is it, though?
It's not, it's not.
I would say it is...
Construction.
Yeah.
Maybe I'll take a couple more andesite casings.
Oh, no, I picked it up.
The lever we don't need.
Or that one.
Oh, we can burn it!
I keep forgetting we have delete options here.
Oh, yeah.
That feels amazing.
Don't need this now.
Or that.
Even though it's kinda nice to have.
Give me some wood.
Such a weird limitation that you can't...
strip these when you have a shield, you know?
Oh, wait.
Yeah, that's good.
Fourteen andesite casings.
Let me think if there's anything else.
We have shafts for the belts.
We have depots, basins...
And...
I'm trying to envision the whole thing now.
Let me actually review.
Strip wood with deployer and axe.
Got it.
That one we can do.
Deploy andesite alloy on stripped wood.
Got it.
And...
Mixing andesite and sink iron nuggets for andesite alloy.
Oh, wait a minute.
Mix andesite and sink for andesite alloy.
No heating required.
But...
Wait a minute.
Do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do.
Right, I can also do that.
Hmm.
Let me see here.
Andesite and sink iron...
Wait, that works?
Did I read that right?
Right.
Okay, yeah.
It's just weird that it's mixing, you know?
It boggles my mind every time I see this.
Because it doesn't make any sense, logically, that if you mix something, you know...
We probably need water, too.
Actually, maybe we don't.
I'm not sure.
But it doesn't matter.
We can use iron nuggets or sink nuggets.
Okay, this is actually going to be a limitation, because we don't have a lot of this.
I guess we'd have to design it in a way where, if this doesn't happen, it'll still work.
I can just put in stuff at various stages of the assembly line.
Depending on what I have, and it'll come out the way I want it, you know?
That's the plan, at least.
Yeah, that's good.
Then we have all this.
Yep.
Power source?
Let's use...
Hmm, what is something that really pollutes the environment?
I need something non-green.
Can I not burn coal to spin a rod?
I would love to do that.
I will not get distracted.
I think we're good.
We just need an axe now, actually.
Let's make a, uh...
What do we have?
We can make a diamond?
No, we can't, actually.
We can make an iron axe.
Let's do that.
Iron axe.
Boom.
I think we're ready!
Let's fucking do it, man!
The factory is a-coming!
We gotta find a location for it, though.
We need maximum pollution.
Maximum destruction of the environment.
Where do we do it?
Definitely near the water, so we can pollute the water with chemicals and toxins.
Right?
Maybe down here, near the water?
Although it would be cool to have it- Oh, what are you doing here?
Get out of here.
Maybe on the other side of the lake or something, and then we'd have to get there by- I don't know, bridge or something.
That could be cool.
Uh, over here is a bad spot.
I don't wanna be near the beach.
Because we're gonna have blankets there and margaritas later.
That's in the works.
So I think it's gotta be over here somewhere.
Not too far away either, right?
Because it needs to make sense.
Maybe right here.
I like this spot.
Let's do it.
So you first gotta put down the rods, apparently.
Look at that rod.
Coming out of the tree.
Excited to see me.
Now we need the belt.
Hey, actually, I need a rod on the other side first.
Right?
Isn't that how that works?
Let me do it like this.
Here we go!
You ready?
Oh!
Yo!
Look at that!
My first belt.
That's amazing.
Now let's spin it.
Oh, we gotta- Yeah, I forgot about the power source.
You know what?
Maybe I'll take my windmill back here.
And take it with me.
Because this whole stuff over there was temporary anyway.
No, actually it's not.
Because it's gonna be used for the elevator.
This stays.
But maybe some of it we can disassemble.
Maybe a water wheel.
It's a little boring, but you know.
It is what it is.
Where's the water wheel?
There it is.
We can even make a large water wheel!
Dude, we should do that.
The bigger the better.
Just need wood for that.
Super easy.
Uh, let's take this.
Let's take this.
That should be enough.
A large water wheel.
Let's ponder on it!
But is it not just gonna be the same though?
They draw a force from adjacent water currents.
Yeah?
Sure.
What else is new?
Covering additional sites will not improve its kinetic output.
Okay.
These rotate only at half the speed of regular water wheels?
What?
Why am I building this?
But provide a substantially higher stress capacity.
Ah.
Hold on.
Spam color.
Get away from me.
Hit so many of those.
It's so annoying.
I missed what it says.
Use wood planks on the wheel to change its appearance.
Yeah, I don't want to do that.
This is ugly!
Who wants that color?
That's disgusting.
That's pretty good.
I like that one.
Oh, that's nice.
That's a good color.
Okay.
I've yet to really understand how this stress capacity actually, you know, works with the gameplay.
In full detail, I mean.
Let's clean up this inventory real quick.
Don't need this.
I guess we don't need a shield.
This is one more slot.
We can have three.
Or these.
Flipboard is essential, of course.
Do we have the deployers?
We do.
Well, nothing else to it.
You know what?
Maybe I'll grab some water on the way because I think we may need it for the mixers.
Oh, we also need a saw!
To strip, right?
No, we don't.
We can do that with the deployer.
That's why I have the axe.
Um...
Get the water.
I'm gonna take from here.
Great.
Oh, I also had this.
I actually saw some missing water here.
There you go.
Now I take this water instead.
And I think it should make sense.
So we should have the water wheel near the water.
Maybe we even make a little creek.
Or something.
You know?
But I guess it would have to come up from the top of the mountain for it to make any sense.
I know!
It doesn't matter!
To me, it does.
I think it's cool.
Okay?
This is how I like to enjoy things.
I'm gonna make a little stream come down from the mountain.
I think that could look really nice.
No, that's not great looking.
Diorite bridge.
That's the machine.
It wasn't me.
It was the machine.
Let's say it come down here.
It comes down from here.
The source is coming from inside the mountain somewhere.
This is like a mountain spring.
The water just magically appears up here.
You know?
It comes out right here.
That's where the...
That's where it starts.
It's gonna go down like this.
And we gotta be careful not to let the water flow freely all over the place.
See, right now...
We can have a bit of a drop here!
We make a little water drop, also called a waterfall.
Makes so much sense, actually.
And it goes down like that.
Maybe we'll expand it, like...
in girth a little later.
Is the water gonna flow weirdly here?
No, it's fine.
See, this right here is problematic.
Or is it?
Maybe not.
Oi!
Yo!
Oh my god!
Oh!
Dude, dude!
We're gonna make...
We're gonna make a little water trough!
That go...
It's like...
Aqueduct!
Made out of wood!
Dude!
Hold on.
We're doing this.
Uh...
I need...
I need this.
I need wood.
I'll be back.
This is...
Okay, this is it, okay?
The water would've come down here naturally and fallen down there.
But I, the great engineer, I decided to redirect the natural flow of water this way.
What do you say to that?
Also, this is ugly right now.
We're gonna remove this.
I dislike that.
Oh, man.
I need wood now.
And you know what?
I think we're gonna end up using flapjacks for this one.
I have 43 of them, but maybe I don't wanna use those.
I would love to use normal flapjacks.
Let me see what these look like.
Fuck.
What are their real names?
I keep forgetting, dude.
Uh...
Trapdoors.
No, I don't like those either.
Oh, no.
I...
I need the, uh...
Spruce?
Maybe there's something in create that can be used here.
Something that is nice.
Table covers, maybe.
What about a pipe?
That's what they're made for.
But then again, you don't wanna pipe...
It's a little too...
Pipey, you know?
I want it to look the way I want it to look.
I may just have to go find some spruce.
But I honestly can't tell the difference between spruce and dark oak.
Like, what is the difference even?
I don't know where to find that.
It's, like, impossible.
Um...
We haven't gone this way in a while.
Let me just...
I'm gonna go on a quick mini-adventure.
No.
Let's start off...
with the...
with the shitty flapjacks.
I'm okay with it.
I'm too excited.
I need to do this now.
I can't get distracted, right?
It's important.
The work we do matters.
Oh, I should have brought some actual...
wood.
Dude, maybe...
slabs, actually.
I'm gonna use slabs.
And to make slabs...
I forgot what you needed.
Just these, right?
24.
What?
Oh.
This just looked different.
Man, I'm running out of space here.
I don't need these sink nuggets.
I do need this, I think.
It's just good to have, you know?
Do that, and then the rest goes in there.
Oh, and this is what goes in here, too.
Alright, now we're good.
Gotta go sleep.
Maybe I'll even put the wheel on that bridge.
Imagine how that's gonna look.
I got a little baby.
Nope, that's a...
regular-sized...
human.
I mean, zombie.
He's dead, though.
Oh!
Maybe the next thing I enchant is my bow.
I need to get a bow with power on it.
We gotta make it powerful.
Um, let me think.
Probably, like...
here?
This is all work in progress.
This dark oak will be replaced.
This is just the start.
Now, the question is, is the water even gonna travel far enough to get across?
I don't know.
Guess we'll find out.
Isn't it, like, uh...
ten or so blocks?
So it goes here.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten?
I think it's, like, ten.
Or maybe it's eight.
I feel like eight or ten is in my mind.
From somewhere.
Uh...
Now for these.
No.
No!
Wait, how am I gonna do this?
This is...
This is weird.
Do I really gotta do this first?
No!
I lost it.
Whatever.
Can't have it be too easy, huh?
There we go.
Gotta be a better way to do this.
Maybe not.
Doesn't matter.
I figured it out.
Remember, I did something like this in...
my last house.
I can't wait to release the water up there and see what happens.
Let's assume it works.
Uh...
No, let's just try it real quick.
Gonna come from there, right?
Ah, crap!
So it was eight.
Right?
One...
two, three, four, five, six, seven...
And then the last one I didn't count, so eight.
Oh, man.
But that's okay.
Oh, right.
Before I release the water...
Give me this.
How do I do this?
I think I just make dirt.
Like that.
Because this dirt is part of this now, you know?
This was natural.
Nothing artificial here.
This is part of it.
Right?
This happens to be perfectly aligned here.
For the bridge.
That should do it.
Maybe we even have a little...
Something there.
Oh, no.
Wait, what?
This...
How the fuck is that gonna work?
Okay, so it goes down.
And then we have that ugliness.
Man, it's the slaps again!
The slaps suck!
Worst item in the game!
Look at that!
Whoever designed these slaps needs to be slapped.
Christ almighty.
Like, what even...
Okay, maybe stairs!
Dude.
Stairs are the answer.
Cover up that stone.
Oh, this looks so nice.
We need some kind of transition here, though.
This is a little too...
Immediate.
Right?
I even have stairs.
Amazing.
I'll take some fences, maybe, too?
No.
Nobody shall enter my home.
Would be cool if you could put a padlock on the door.
Oh, here it is.
This should work beautifully.
Oh, Minecraft, how I hate you at times.
Unbelievable.
I guess we get rid of that, too.
And then we do this.
Well, now you're angled the wrong way, of course.
Oh, my God.
Oh, man.
Hey, that works.
Good enough for me!
No.
No, no, no, no, no.
Cool.
It's good.
It's beautiful.
And that water needs to come from upstairs.
Let's do that now.
This is gonna be crazy.
You think it's gonna work first try?
Or is it gonna go wild?
I'm not even gonna modify it.
This will work.
First try.
Oh, it's beautiful.
Look at that.
Here it comes!
Ha ha ha!
Hooey!
That is amazing.
Mountain source!
Clean and fresh.
Now, what do we do?
We can't keep going down, right?
That's the problem.
What we could do...
Is...
We could keep going down.
Or we simply, um...
Grab some rotation from here.
You know what?
We need some flapjacks up here, too.
We're not done flapping.
Just like those birds.
Oh, no!
There we go.
Wait, why did...
Why did it look like that?
That's ugly.
There we go.
That is actually so pretty.
I almost want to shed a tear.
Now.
Shovel.
The water comes this way.
And then it stops at some point, right?
I guess I...
You know what, actually?
Let's not bring it down too far.
Wait a minute!
We can use a pump!
And this makes sense, too!
You know?
Because check...
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Oh, oh my god.
Watch this.
I figured it out.
This is it.
Yeah?
Wait a minute.
It's gonna end up looking weird.
No, it's not.
It's actually fine.
We just need some water now.
And I don't have it.
Ah, crap.
I need infinite water.
So that means we need three water buckets.
That's...
That's gonna be annoying.
I'm gonna make two more water buckets, just because I'm so lazy.
What are you gonna do about it?
Okay.
We're gonna make a tiny, tiny pond.
At the end of that.
And you may think...
But that doesn't make sense.
If the water keeps flowing down, where's all the water going?
It's going up the pipe, baby!
Baby, it's a balance!
We keep pumping!
Maintain the water level!
Think about it!
Are you thinking about it?
Oh, uh, we need to make this infinite.
Here.
There.
Now we have infinite water.
Sure.
Ah, wait.
I messed up.
Got a take from the center.
Now we put it here.
And then we put it here.
And then we put one here.
And one over there.
And perhaps one over...
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh!
We messed up.
And one over there.
We did that already!
This one.
We did it!
Wait!
It's looking weird!
We have an error.
Huh?
Wait, is it correct?
Why is this flowing that way?
Ah, there it is!
Look at that.
Clean, fresh, mountain spring water.
Coming down into a little pond.
But the pond is too square!
It looks unnatural.
We gotta make it irregular.
Maybe something like that.
Now this...
This is pleasing.
That's what I'm talking about.
Something like that, you know?
It's the nature that's beautiful here.
But then, of course...
I'm gonna come in.
And I'm gonna pollute it.
We're gonna put in pipes!
We're gonna smoke it.
We're gonna add dope to it.
Ha ha ha ha!
We're gonna spike their water supply!
Look at that pond looks weird now.
It's too tetris-y.
There we go.
Fixed.
Oh, yeah.
Nice.
And now we grab the water.
But for that, we need a pump.
I'll be back.
We can stack these now.
We're gonna pump it up.
We're gonna spit it out...
into another stream.
And it's just for a little faucet to drink.
And then we're gonna put in a windmill...
and get some power from that.
That's the point.
And it's beautiful.
Maybe a fluid tank on the way as well.
No, mechanical pump.
Put this over here.
So, fluid pipe.
Let me think.
Mechanical pump.
That's all we need, really.
Oh, wait a minute!
We can't drive the mechanical pump without the power!
We need a wheel to drive the pump...
so we can drive a wheel to drive the factory!
Damn!
That's deep.
I hadn't thought of that.
This kind of puts a wrench in my plans.
I guess we can just put a wheel over here.
That also feels kind of nasty, doesn't it?
Should we put a wheel here?
Should we put a wheel?
We could put a wheel right here!
Maybe we don't need a big wheel.
How big is it, really?
Oh my god, it's big!
I wasn't expecting that!
That's a massive fucking wheel!
Alright.
Wait, no, no!
This doesn't work at all!
Oh, no!
Hmm.
I mean, I guess I could just...
plop it down there?
Further down?
Yeah, why not?
Let me block this water for now.
Quick blockage.
Good.
So we're gonna put it...
I guess, like...
here?
Whoops.
Clear blocks for placement.
What do you mean?
But I'm...
I'm wanting to put it that way.
Can I not do that?
Wait, I need to understand how this placement works.
Oh, so it's like a 3x3.
Okay.
Oh, I see.
Okay, yeah.
Yeah, I see how we don't have room.
Oh, the other way!
Stop trying to place it horizontally!
Wait, I guess I could do that?
Why?
Why don't I do that?
Wait, maybe this is better?
No, actually.
It looks kind of weird.
I think I need to destroy blocks to get down there.
It sounds ridiculous, but...
Fucking block placements are so unintuitive.
Hey, there we go.
Oh my god, it's perfect.
Isn't it?
Damn!
I somehow nailed that.
Wow.
Not bad.
Okay, now.
We don't need these.
We need the aesthetics of the wheel.
Oh, it's spinning that way.
No, no.
That's wrong.
That's not physics.
Let me physics it.
Hit the finish of the car, dude.
Oh, yeah!
We're not done.
Dude, actually looks...
Oh, wait.
Oh, hold on.
We got leakage.
Is that why?
Hold on, we need to inspect this.
Yo!
I need rope!
But I don't have it.
Why you do this?
How does that work?
Wait, I need to look at this.
Oh, it's falling.
Oh, okay.
Wait, that works?
Why?
Why can't...
How can I put that there?
That's crazy.
Hey, what about a flapjack?
Huh?
Not bad!
Flapjacks to the rescue.
Another common flapjack W.
They're racking those up.
Although, I will say...
Maybe the wheel should be higher.
Or more this way.
You know what I mean?
Nah, actually, it's perfect.
It's just that this right here, it looks weird to me.
So what we can do is...
Why does it look like that, though?
What is this little ugly thingy?
Oh!
Oh.
Wait, let me turn off the stream.
What happens now?
It doesn't spin anymore because I blocked this part.
That's good.
Stop the water.
Let's see what happens when I release it now.
Okay, well.
I guess there's nothing we can do about that.
I'm gonna put in the flapjacks.
No.
We wanna see the wheel, right?
It's just that the water will spill over the sides here.
Will it not?
This is fine.
I have decided...
There's still a stream in the wrong way here.
And is this one here?
Nah, shit.
There we go.
Good enough, dude!
We're done here.
Now the question is...
How are we gonna get this rotation going?
This is the next major problem.
Well, here it is.
This is the wheel.
We're gonna grab it.
Oh, also, we gotta go to bed.
Yeah, this is too dangerous.
It's too dark.
I bring a bed from home.
And a little sleeping bag.
I think I left it here.
Kinda wanna bring a little chest as well.
Like a little work chest.
Chest away from home.
Sleep under the stars.
Actually so cool.
Okay, here we go.
It starts.
Now the question is, how do we do this in a smart way?
I guess the first step would be to put a small wheel here.
Like that.
Because then it's gonna...
Wait, no, that doesn't make any sense, actually.
It only makes sense if we put this first.
Okay.
Then we put a little rod.
Mmm, actually...
No, what if we were to...
No, keep that.
That's fine.
What?
No.
Didn't mean to do that.
Wait, we can just fl...
Hold on.
I got an idea.
Hey!
Better!
That's it!
Now we're talking!
Now we can really see the wheel, too.
Not bad.
Let me get rid of that one.
And we put a little wheel here.
Look at that!
Now the question is, how do we want to transport this?
Um, I guess there's the massive rod?
I could also use a belt, obviously, but that's a bit weird.
I think a rod makes more sense.
Um, so let's do...
Uh-oh!
Oh!
Don't fall!
Oh, crap.
That was close.
I want to turn this 90 degrees, but I don't have a gearbox with me, and I'm too lazy to go get one.
So perhaps we simply...
No?
Oh, wait!
Uh!
Dude, I need to go get a gearbox.
Gearbox it is.
I was thinking, maybe also bring my wrench.
Because sometimes you can rotate these on the spot, and it's going to be quite useful to do that.
Hey, brother!
Oh, you went somewhere.
I was going to murder you.
You're lucky.
Oh, my God.
This inventory!
Whew!
All this wood is not needed anymore.
It just ain't.
Let me think.
This one.
And gearboxes.
Vertical gearbox.
But we also need horizontal.
We actually need a bunch of that.
What?
Ah, it's just called the gearbox.
Give me five of those.
That should do it.
And we also have so many rods, we can do almost anything.
The question now is, where do we lead these rods?
Like, where should the factory be?
That's a big question.
We still gotta pump this water out, though.
And we can do that with this now.
Yo, we used it on the way there.
Ooh, that's smart.
That's actually so good.
You know what?
We need water back there anyway, right?
We're gonna need it for the mixers, I guess?
Oh, it's perfect.
It's almost too perfect.
So, gearbox now.
Like that.
And then...
We're gonna...
Let me actually first figure out where to put this pump.
So the pump requires something to rotate like that.
So that means...
Where do I want the pipe?
Is probably the question.
Like here.
You know?
Sucking up the water.
And then we put this guy here.
Now we need to...
Oh wait, it's angled wrong.
So now we use the machine here.
There we go.
Yeah.
So we...
I'm trying to see if I can unline it.
I guess I could also just put this over here instead.
What's gonna come from...
here?
I kinda wanna go up as well.
I feel like we're not quite...
there yet, you know?
Let's put a big wheel.
Like that.
And a small wheel up top.
Look how fast it is now.
Wait, did I use all my wheels?
Oh shit, I used them for the gearboxes!
Oh no.
Give me some quick wood.
Whoops, that was unintended.
Oh, I need a...
Oh man.
Wait, what do you mean?
Oh, what am I doing?
Cock.
There we go.
Fixed.
Don't know what I was doing just now.
But it's okay.
Alright, so now we can have this...
fast rotation...
into a box right here.
And it's gonna look a little better too.
In my opinion.
Or...
Check this out.
Vertical.
Onto a...
Wait, we need another vertical then.
I mean, it's not...
You know.
It's not...
Ah, I don't like that actually.
I hate it.
Terrible.
Normal gearbox.
For normal people.
Here comes the rod.
Although, wouldn't it be cool if we had this underground?
Now that I think about it.
This part is not gonna be visible.
This is the invisible part.
So we're actually gonna...
put the small wheel downstairs.
Like that.
And then we're gonna have...
Uh...
This lane go this way.
Oh, that's perfect.
That's perfect.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Good.
Very nice.
Gearbox down here.
Like that.
Give me my shovel.
Oh, crap.
Block it.
Look how cool that looks.
That's right there.
Ah, it's gonna go right...
Okay.
Yeah, the stream is a little weird.
It's gonna go in like that instead.
Needs to be one further down.
And you know what?
I can do it.
Like that.
Yep.
Now we gearbox.
Oh!
I lost something!
Oh.
Oh, no.
Oh, I thought I was stuck!
Here?
And now we can rod as much as we want.
Right?
Wait, hold on.
Why does that work?
Oh, wait!
I miscalculated!
We can actually go one higher.
It's fine.
Whoops.
We're totally cool.
Like
that.
So the question is, where are we now?
Oh, look at it!
Here it is!
Gearbox.
Vertical.
The rotation is coming!
Let's actually bring it over.
Let me see.
It'll be there.
Quick sleep.
Can I rotate that, actually?
How come my fucking shovel keeps getting unequipped?
I don't understand.
I'm losing my mind.
Vertical.
Here it comes!
Oh, no.
And I guess we need another vertical.
Ah, but...
Yeah, here's the problem, right?
Here's the problem.
Maybe we have something like this instead.
With a small wheel next to it.
Can that be done?
No, that's not how that works.
Let me try a...
normal gearbox.
No.
Oh, wait!
I had to do here and go up.
Because then I could go that way and have a wheel.
Oh, right.
So I was actually doing it correctly.
I see how it is now.
I gotta get used to this, you know?
Now we shaft.
into a vertical.
Can I rotate that?
Nice!
And here comes the rod!
Actually!
Wait, why can't I...
put the small wheel here?
Oh, I can, but...
I guess I can bring it down one.
That way we get a bit more speed as well.
Not too bad.
Oh yeah, that's gonna suck fast!
That's a fast one.
Let's make it pretty.
Now the question is...
What do we do with this water?
Let's check if it actually works.
This should, uh, pump water out.
Didn't I have a receptacle?
Just a normal pipe, I guess.
This should bring water up.
I think.
Oh wait, it's pointing the wrong way.
Now it should.
Oh, yeah, yeah, you can even see the little...
Okay.
Here we go.
That's it.
Nice!
Good shit.
I like it.
This is so dope!
Dude, I love knowing that there's like a rod down here.
Just doing things, you know?
That's exciting to me.
Okay.
We cover it up.
Like this.
No evidence...
of anything.
Cool.
So dope.
I'm trying to think if I could have done this even...
in a more cool way.
Actually, there is one thing I could have done.
Yeah, check it out.
Instead of doing it like this...
we can make it even more elegant.
And we need a little bit of room here.
Now the big wheel.
Oh, it's a little too far down.
Okay.
But I guess I could maybe...
look at that.
Even better.
What do you say to that?
And we're gonna make it even better now with some casing.
Yo, dude!
Oh, that's sick!
Yo.
Can I case more?
I'm gonna case this guy.
Yes!
Oh, man.
What else should I be casing?
No, that's bad.
Bad case.
Bad case!
Get it out of here.
Terrible case.
Oh, shit.
Stuck.
There we go.
I don't like this rod just terminating, though.
Don't like Terminator rods.
So we're gonna have it do that.
In fact, we could just do it like...
Yeah!
Oh, my God, bro.
Although, I do want to see this, you know?
It is kind of exciting.
You know, it's okay.
I like that.
It's a good look.
Yeah.
Now we just need this.
And then, maybe one more.
And, of course, this will be replaced by oak later.
Or, I mean, spruce.
Spruce is the ideal, you know?
It's also gonna fit this color of these wheels more.
Or we make it industrial, you know?
Like iron or...
Oh, we can also make metal flapjacks.
Hmm.
Options.
But this is good, though.
Water is coming!
I just don't...
Oh, wait.
Oh, that's actually kind of dope.
Can we stop this for a sec here?
Oh, no.
Let's just pipe it.
Oh, wait.
So the water goes that way.
We need to bring it into the factory.
Right?
And the factory is over here.
This is...
It's actually right here.
Maybe a little further.
Do I bring the pipe up a little bit again?
Oh, don't you dare.
Don't you dare.
I need to turn this off.
We can't have this right now.
Yeah.
Maybe one higher.
It's not pretty.
Uh...
I don't think it can actually pump this infinitely long distances, right?
You can see the water particles.
Wow!
It works here!
Okay!
But it would be a shame to waste this rotational energy.
So maybe we bring this along with us, too.
You know?
But it's also kind of satisfying to have a windmill over here, I guess, at some point.
Right.
Now...
Time for the factory!
Uh...
I'm thinking maybe we start by making the assembly lines.
And then we can make the housing around it later.
Because otherwise, I'll have to redo the housing.
And I don't know how big things are gonna be.
So, you know.
Yeah.
Let's just make it and see what happens.
I'm also gonna flatten this area a little bit.
This needs to be flat for the factory.
My shovel is about to break.
Also good to get some birch, I guess.
The nasty trees I'm gonna save with the saw.
Or take care of it with the saw.
Let's also deploy this while we're here.
Temporary workplace thingy.
I don't need...
I'm just gonna take the stuff I need.
I need that.
I need this.
That one.
This one.
We need more piping.
I actually kinda need it all.
I'll be right back.
I gotta take a piss.
Okay.
It's time.
I'm thinking we just do something simple at first.
Like, we make a simple assembly line in, like, one dimension.
Best way to learn it, I guess.
And then we can always overcomplicate it later.
When we need to.
How's it night already?
I just slept.
Yeah, I gotta get rid of...
Oh, there he goes.
Yeah.
As expected.
I gotta go make a new one.
Thankfully, I have two diamonds.
I can even make two.
I also think I really should go to level 30 real quick.
Because if I die, I lose it all, right?
Do I need this saw for anything, actually?
Ah, I can go grab it if I do.
Put you in there.
Um...
When did I come back?
Oh, yeah, white.
Right.
I needed the...
Diamonds.
Make shovels.
I'm gonna make two.
Leave one behind.
Man, that's a tall-ass birch tree!
Isn't that, like, super unusual?
What the hell is that?
Oh, there's another one here.
Maybe it's not that weird.
It just looked so tall.
That's probably enough space for now.
Okay.
Since we have the rotational energy...
Let's just use it.
Right?
We even have it down here.
Look, we can take from that one.
Like that.
Ah, we gotta go a little further with that.
That's not enough.
I guess we can just have a long-ass rotation that we can use later.
Like this.
A little more.
Oops.
Right?
Perfect.
Now we need a vertical box.
Then we bring it up.
And here we have it.
So the first step of this process is going to be...
Let's check.
What's the first step here?
I guess we need wood that we need to strip with the deployer and an axe.
Right?
That's one thing.
Let me just double-check things.
No?
Andeside...
This is what I want to make, right?
So the final one is andeside alloy on stripped wood.
Okay, that's easy.
So we need stripped wood that's going to come from...
Oh!
Oh, wait.
Oh, oh, okay.
I do need a saw.
I was like, do I not just put an axe in the deployer's hand and it's going to strip it?
That's why I brought the axe.
Well, there you go.
So I need this thing.
Where are you?
There you are.
Mechanical saw.
All right.
And I guess I don't need this axe anymore then.
We can put it over here.
Maybe you can do it actually with the deployer.
It's just weird that it wouldn't show up.
Kind of want to make this pipe green.
I think I like green more.
Okay, so we know how to do that now.
But before we get to that, we also need to get something else, right?
Andesite.
You know what, actually?
Maybe it's easier if we start with the end goal and things are going to come in from the sides, right?
Ooh, that's actually maybe better.
I think I like that layout more.
Yep.
So the end one is the Andesite.
This one.
And we can do that like this.
So let's make that depot and deployer.
Depot...
I have it.
Here.
And deployer.
I got plenty.
Let's say that happens
here.
Right?
It's probably going to change position later, but for now, it's fine.
there.
Deployer.
Wonderful.
I kind of like how that looks even.
We can put some metal in there later or something.
Oh!
It jumped up on the thing!
Stop that.
Okay, so this needs to be from that angle.
I guess I can just rotate it, right?
Wait, no.
Yeah.
And then, yeah.
That's actually great.
Except it needs to be one more that way.
I wonder if I can just angle it if I stay over here.
Ah, that works.
Beautiful.
Very nice.
Look the way it comes up and then we vertical it.
That looks weird.
But, all right.
Very nice.
So that's happening.
Let's try and see if we can use a belt on this, shall we?
Oh, I can just wait, I can just place it like that?
No.
Okay.
That's weird.
Why am I able to do that?
So this should just work, right?
But wait a sec.
When it comes here, it's gonna be stuck, isn't it?
Oh, wait a minute.
We don't even need the depot.
Fucking hell.
The belt is the depot in this case.
Of course.
Wow.
Wowie.
Also, I have 64 now.
Wait, that counts as one belt?
Okay, guys.
I think I may have too much.
Like, this is way too much belt.
I thought this was gonna count for one belt each, dude.
Whoa.
Okay.
We will never run out of belts.
Now the question is, can I also drive this via this?
Probably if I put the rod right there instead.
And I put a vertical gearbox.
here.
Oh, I'll probably have to do this first.
No.
Wait, what?
Get off!
How do I take it off?
Maybe with the wrench?
Okay.
I don't know.
Destroy it.
Very confusing.
There we go.
Rod.
This should work.
Except, wait, it's going the wrong way.
Hmm.
Do we care?
Maybe it's fine.
Maybe that is the end over there.
Let's say that, actually.
Then it comes from this side instead.
Yo!
Can I go on it?
Don't punch me!
Aw.
Okay, so the question now is...
Let's see if we can make it work.
So we give this guy a bunch of andesite alloy, right?
There you go.
And now I give you some wood.
Also, let's go to bed, shall we?
This is a disaster out here.
Thank you.
We need to strip this first.
Oh, dude!
Are you ready?
We're going to strip it and apply it at the same time.
Stripping is axe.
No, it's the...
You know?
And you are there.
Can I just...
I guess I would have to...
Oh, god.
Ponder!
A very fast ponder here.
Aha!
Just as I suspected.
Oh, no!
That just removes it.
Okay.
Oh, so that means I would have a rod on each side.
Makes sense.
I lost my train of thought.
So we need this.
But, like...
Here?
And there?
Is that right?
Why can't...
Oh, wait.
What?
Huh?
Okay.
Just plop the saw down, son.
Yes!
Oh, that needs to spin spinny spin as well.
That makes sense.
Can I not use...
Wait.
Well, there it is!
Except...
Hold on, this is spinning the wrong way now.
Yeah, this is spinning that way.
That's not good.
We have a problem.
Well, you know, there is a solution here.
No!
It's gonna end up spinning the same way!
Damn.
Oh, look at it!
It's going along the belt.
What if I just...
Can I just turn that around or something?
Like, instead of...
Can I just flip it that way?
Oh, so right now, this is on that side?
Let me see.
Maybe I can do that.
Now it's over here, so...
It doesn't matter, I guess.
It's all about the spin direction.
Oh, no.
How do we do this in an elegant way?
Gearboxes, maybe?
No, it's still spinning the wrong way, of course.
I mean, okay, there's an obvious solution.
It doesn't feel good, though, you know?
Wait, what?
Oh, I need to get...
Oh, sh...
Oh, but then I can't...
Oh.
It works!
And I don't care.
It's temporary.
Okay.
So now they come in like this, right?
They're going to have another shaft here.
Oh, we have it already, so...
Let's just put it like there.
Oh, wait.
This also needs to spin, of course.
Oh, yeah.
Dude, I'm already so excited about this.
This is obviously disgusting, and...
I hate it, but, you know.
It's fine.
For now.
This can be done better, by the way.
Wait a second!
Oh, I...
Oh.
We got people.
I'm going to intrude on my...
factory?
Maybe you just came to get a job.
You heard of the industrialization, you know?
You wanted to be a part of it.
Ha-ha!
Team kill!
Dude, I'm the superior marksman.
They had no shot!
Wow.
I dealt with that.
Yeah, that's expected.
But hey.
Wait, that...
Wait, how does that even work?
Oh, it does...
Yeah, it makes sense, I guess.
I've got a...
Man, I'm already, like...
losing my damn mind over this.
Let's find a better solution to this.
What if we were to simply...
Oh, wait a minute.
Hold on.
I have an idea.
Shit!
You're kidding!
Shut up, sheep.
Oh!
That hurts?
You can't walk on that.
That makes sense, I guess.
No.
I mean, okay.
I could just take this and move it down the line, maybe?
Don't I have...
Hold on.
Don't I have, like, a block that changes direction of a rotation?
I feel like that's a thing.
I feel like I've seen that.
That has to exist.
I'm pretty sure I made it, too.
Maybe that one.
What was that?
Relay rotation by following it.
No, that's, like, timing.
I don't like that.
Threshold switch.
Clutch is the one that stops it.
I think I need something like that.
But just not sequenced.
Wait, directional gear shift?
Just give me a normal-ass gear shift.
Cock wheel.
We need dust.
Needs redstone.
Ah.
Not elegant.
Well, maybe it's okay.
Uh, gear shift.
Now we need this.
Now we just need power on that.
Oh, this is ugly!
Wait a minute!
Maybe there's a way to, uh...
You know how you can store a charge with a bulb?
Maybe you can permanently change the direction.
Or, like, permanently just charge it and then get rid of these later?
Oh, that doesn't make sense.
We still need the rotation.
Damn.
My goodness.
This is turning into...
SPAGHETTI!
There's got to be an easier way to do this.
Uh, man.
I think I'm overthinking this.
Let me get rid of...
If I just put one here...
So it's going...
It's going that way.
That way.
Wrong.
But we just need to get rid of that one.
But then the belt won't work, right?
Ah, man.
You know what?
We...
We already had the solution.
It's alright.
Just...
Just fucking do that.
It's not pretty!
But it works.
Man.
That's ugly.
Anyway.
Uh, now I can essentially take this one.
Or even...
Wait.
That way.
Oh my god.
This is such a mess.
No, that's wrong as well.
I need...
This one.
No!
God...
Damn, dude!
Why is this shit so fucking difficult?
It's blowing my mind.
It's going to be the wrong way again.
And how is the date going by so fast?
It's like five minutes.
And the day is over.
That's my last mutton.
I've soon consumed all the energy I have.
Uh...
Dude.
I never thought this would be that difficult.
A fucking belt!
Let me think.
Let's say I just...
Okay.
Let's say I just have a rod going that way.
Right?
Let me...
Let me imagine that.
I'm imagining it.
It's going like that.
And if it spins this way...
Can I not just simply...
Actually, let me just do that while I have rotation here.
Like that.
Let's see.
Let's say I gear shifted.
Or gearbox it.
Okay.
But let's just imagine it was the other one.
Like that.
That one's fixed.
Ah!
Well, then the problem arises!
That's crazy, bro.
Oh, man.
Ah, it's fine!
We just do one of these every time?
Is that really it?
No, we need to, um...
Let me see here.
I guess we can offset it by one every time.
Except in the other direction.
Then, like...
That's...
Gearbox...
And now it's working again.
But that is...
Man, that is some ugly shit!
Wait, how is it this difficult to do?
Crazy, bro.
My brain is not made for this kind of thinking.
I can tell you that.
Like, obviously I can fix it right now.
But I'm trying to think of the bigger picture here, you know?
How I would do this ideally in a situation where I have a long assembly line.
And I'm trying to do it elegantly.
This is what I'm thinking about.
I'm not thinking about this specific problem, you know?
Um...
Maybe it is simply with redstone, you know?
And you'd use the, uh...
The gear thingy.
The shift.
Because then you can, you know, apply redstone and not on the ones that you need it on.
I think it is simply...
Like, I think it's just that simple.
And it's not even that hard, you know?
Just put a little lever on top.
Yeah.
Let's do that.
That way it can stay on.
And then the next one we keep off.
The next one we have on.
And so on and so forth.
This takes...
Okay, good.
Now we need levers.
Wait a minute.
Oops.
Analog lever.
No, I want a normal lever.
Cobblestone stick.
It's in my box.
Sticks I have.
Lever.
Let's make five.
Done.
This back.
There we go.
Stack these.
Okay.
We got a solution, but it's still not, like, nice, you know?
Now, basically, the idea is this.
Oh, but wait.
These are right next to each other.
Is that a problem?
It's not a problem, actually.
Trying to think of the best way to do this.
Do I do rods or not?
I think rods.
I need more gear boxes.
Man, gear boxes are kind of expensive to make.
Four cock wheels for that.
Nuts.
Okay.
Now watch.
There it is.
It's kind of nice, I guess.
It's not that bad.
There's a certain, you know, beauty to it.
Yeah, I can appreciate that, actually.
Okay, now for the...
The big deal.
Wait, I'm actually not sure what happened there.
Am I using...
Oh, I'm using...
Okay, I thought it was, like, a free shaft, but it's not.
Yeah, this is fine for now, I guess.
Why is this here?
Okay, I got it.
You ready?
Here we go!
This should work.
What?!
How
does that make any...
Oh, it actually makes total sense.
Oh, my God.
You want the saw to go against the way you're going.
That makes so much sense!
Fuck!
Oh, my God.
I can't believe that.
There we go.
Do we even need these, then?
Hold on.
Yeah, we do.
Yeah.
Ah, that's crazy, bro.
Where's my...
lever?
Okay.
You ready?
Here we go.
And now...
Yo!
Okay, that is fucking great.
Oh, man.
All right!
We're making progress.
Okay, good.
So, that's done.
What's the next part?
We gotta bring things in, you know?
Let me see.
Check the clipboard.
This, we...
Okay, so this one is actually wrong.
Strip wood with...
Let's just rind...
Rind...
Right...
The...
Saw.
Okay.
Mix andesite and zinc slash iron nuggets for andesite alloy.
Interesting.
So, basically, we need a way to bring in andesite alloys to this hand...
Automatically.
The question is...
How we do dat?
That sounds crazy.
Let me see how that works.
Can I...
Is it shoots?
Maybe.
How do I give you an item?
It's gotta be like shoots.
Hold on.
Let me see here.
Transportation.
Shoot?
Let's see it.
They can transport items vertically from and to inventories.
Yeah.
But...
So, like a hopper, I guess.
Right?
Using the wrench and window can be created.
That's cool.
I like that a lot.
Let's just test that.
Let's see if it works.
Or we can make it even more simple and just use...
Ah, but no, wait.
No, wait.
I was about to say hopper.
But if we Tom Holland it, then we can't really use an assembly line.
Because the whole point is that we want to mix it, right?
And after it's mixed, it needs to come out.
And when it comes out, it is now antiside.
It needs to travel along.
And it needs to be...
No, it needs to be mixed with the...
Sink nuggets.
Then it becomes antiside alloy.
And then it needs to come out as well afterwards.
How the hell do we do that?
Now, that's an interesting question.
Let's bring some baked potatoes.
Fuel or mined?
Okay, let's see here.
What do we have to work with?
Portable storage interface.
Oh, here.
Shoots.
Okay, I think we're good.
Yeah.
That's all I needed.
Let's test it.
I'm in love with this assembly line I made over here.
I think it's so pretty.
Sleep.
I want to sleep on the assembly line.
Dude, I want to go on an assembly line and have...
Mechanical arms.
Put on armor for me.
Just like...
You know, Iron Man or something.
He goes through and...
You know, they put on the shoulder blades.
They put on the helmet.
And I come out the other side, armored and ready for combat.
Imagine that.
Uh...
Okay.
Good.
Let's shoot it.
All right.
Guess we do it from top.
But, uh...
Wait, wait, wait.
Oh, oh!
Oh, dude!
We can go up with this, right?
That was the whole point.
So, let's say I do...
Um...
Yeah.
No!
Stop it!
I need to ponder this again.
Vertically from and to...
Okay.
But from you said.
How?
Maybe that's explained here.
Using the wrench, a window can be created.
Okay, yeah, whatever.
Using industrial iron blocks, shoots can be encased.
Now it falls.
But, now...
Maybe next scene.
Oh!
Using encased fans at the top or bottom.
Yeah, okay.
Inspecting shoots with engineer's goggles reveals information about the movement direction.
Good.
Hmm.
Oh!
On the blocked end, items will have to be inserted, taken from the sides.
Dude, I need this thing!
I need that!
Oh my god!
Uh...
Also, I need a fan.
Let's just test this real quick.
What do I have?
I need to see what that looks like again.
Let's see here.
Also, I'm gonna get my goggles, I guess.
That kind of looks like rubber, right?
And it kind of looks like something...
Hmm.
Can I make that?
Let me see if I can make that.
That
one.
Oh!
Brass tunnel?
Kind of looks like it!
Look at the little, uh...
Flappy thingies.
Brass funnel.
Dude, it looks like this, but...
Except it's not brass.
Does it matter?
Contraption controls?
Oh, like to take it horizontally?
I imagine.
Oh!
Anticide funnel?
That's it?
Alloy and kelp.
I got it!
Funnel.
Chaos.
Dude, I have ten.
I didn't mean to make ten.
That's a bit too much.
Maybe.
Oh, I needed a fan.
Fan was important.
Fan.
Propeller.
Okay.
Prop.
Sheets.
You got it!
What was it?
Fan.
Okay.
I think we may have what it takes now.
This thing looks amazing.
Wait a minute!
Hold on.
I can go up with the freaking belts, can't I?
What am I even doing?
Nope.
Stop that.
Oh, wait a minute.
How?
Huh.
Oh, maybe I need to go one higher.
I think I see the whole vision in here.
I know what they want me to do.
Watch this.
Shoot.
There.
And then?
Shaft.
No!
Yes!
And then?
Maybe that's too steep.
Maybe here.
Let's see it.
Oh, okay.
So right there, huh?
You've got it.
Wait.
What?
Okay, you want one more this way?
We can do that.
Yes!
Dude, look at that!
That's fantastic.
It's going to go up here.
It's going to fall down the chute.
Into?
The hand.
Hopefully it works like that.
I mean, we can try and put some stuff in there.
So right now the hand is empty.
Yeah, it's empty.
Now watch.
Oh my god, it works!
Oh!
Amazing!
And you know what?
I bet I can use the funnel to go horizontal instead of down, you know?
Let me test.
So we're going to put this one lower.
Funnel!
Dude, I'm making...
By the way, I totally forgot about the achievements.
Why am I not looking at these?
I still haven't done this!
That's crazy!
Yeah, we...
Okay, hold on.
I need to write this down.
Look!
At advancements!
More.
Now, let's see if this works.
I guess it would have to be at that height.
And I guess the belt needs to...
Hmm.
Actually, I don't know about that.
This looks wrong.
Doesn't it?
Maybe here?
Oh!
That makes sense.
So now, we're gonna have...
belts.
Oh, you can't go down to there?
That's weird.
Really?
What do you mean?
Does that work?
Oh, okay.
I see how it is.
Needs to be one further down.
This should work?
Oh, okay.
So it's 45 degrees.
Jeez.
Alright.
It's consistent like that.
Aha.
Huh?
Why...
Why does that not work?
Stop.
Wait, why the hell can I not connect this?
Also, look at the way this is now enveloping the belt.
I think this is exactly how it needs to be done.
That I don't understand.
Why that doesn't work?
I guess I can...
keep it simple for now.
Maybe do like this.
No, stop.
Ah!
Dude, I'm losing my mind.
Okay, now what?
Show me?
Stop expanding it!
Maybe I need to hold shift or control.
Okay, now!
Okay, what am I not fucking understanding here?
Wait, right-clicking two shafts with a...
Yeah.
That's what I'm doing.
Additional shafts can be added throughout the belt.
Yeah.
Added shafts can be removed using the wrench.
Okay.
Belts cannot connect in arbitrary directions.
Makes sense.
That's not what I tried.
Yes.
Yep.
But you can't go on like this anymore after!
Ah, okay!
You can't connect them!
Fucking hell, okay.
That makes sense.
Okay, good.
But now the problem is, they need to rotate the same direction, which is always a problem here.
You know what, actually?
How about this?
Wait, what did I just take from that?
I thought he had a, um...
Whatever.
There you go.
I'm gonna crank this shit manually!
It's for testing purposes.
I don't need something complicated.
I need, uh...
My crank.
The problem is now, they're gonna rotate.
I need to crank it really fast on one, and then go to the next, and it's gonna be a little weird.
Yeah, that's not gonna work, unless I somehow...
I don't even know if that's gonna work.
I have not calculated the rotations.
Let me quickly sleep.
Here we go.
Ah, it's the opposite way.
Damn it.
I was...
hoping it wasn't gonna be like that.
God damn it.
Okay, maybe stop trying to guess.
I hate this part, because I just wanna fucking test it.
I don't wanna have to figure this out now.
Ah, it's the...
gear shift, isn't it?
Fine.
Lever that.
It works!
Wonderful.
So they can come from the top, they can come from the side.
I love it.
But now I know.
That's good.
Now the question is, how do I do this?
Wait, hold on.
I wonder if this block below it is also counting.
Let's rod it here.
No.
Uh, here.
Stop!
How do I make it not...
There we go.
I guess this is kinda useless now, but you know.
Let's see how this works.
So you're trying to press on that one.
Can I somehow remove that from the belt?
Without...
Ah, there we go.
This is probably just gonna go on the belt, right?
It stopped.
I guess it needs to be maybe one higher.
Oh, that's really weird.
And now this thing is...
Oh, there it is.
I wonder though, if I...
Oh!
Oh my god.
If I extended this a little bit...
Let's use the wrench for that.
Oh, what?
Why doesn't it work now?
I'm losing my...
I'm losing my mind!
Before it extended it!
Now it's removing?
It's happening!
No, never mind.
It was this one.
It's me.
I suck.
Never mind.
Disregard everything I just said.
It's fine.
Put that in.
Okay, now.
Check it out.
You ready?
I'm gonna remove all this.
I'm gonna connect it like a boss.
No, not like that.
Now we belt it.
Now that we have an extra one on that side, watch.
Aw, man!
What if you are gone?
What then?
Would you look at that?
So it was blocking it.
I see.
So I guess we would have to come in before.
Alright.
I have done enough testing.
Let's actually implement.
I forgot what I was even implementing.
So right now we can make strip like that and then it comes in and goes blop.
It becomes a little anticide fella.
Watch this.
There we go.
Wait, what?
What the?
Dude, I am not understanding.
Why is it every configuration except the single one I need?
Oh, there it is.
This I will never understand.
This is the most cryptic shit I've ever experienced in any game.
All right.
This thing needs anticide alloys.
So they're going to come in by assembly line.
Wow.
And the way we're going to do that is we're not going to use a funnel.
Yes, we are going to use a funnel.
Yeah, actually this was the correct situation I had going here.
Yeah, I like that actually.
It was good.
We're going to we're going to keep it.
It comes in like that.
Shaft.
Connect.
Now I need a new shaft.
There.
And then from here.
Shaft.
Connect.
Look at this.
I'm learning.
It's happening.
Now we can take this rotation and bring it over there.
Because we're so smart.
Use that as well.
With a lever.
I need a gearbox.
Tell me I have it.
Damn, I don't have it.
I must have it.
I don't have it.
Not yet.
Did I really run out of rods?
That's surprising.
Rotate.
It doesn't matter.
We can change direction with that.
That's cool.
Gimme.
And there it goes.
Opposite.
Ah, I really need another gearbox.
I don't want to get another gearbox though.
Fine.
No.
We need cocks.
Wood and shaft.
Alright, here I go.
Felling trees again.
I take only what I need.
Wait, shafts.
Yeah, that's good.
Let's make 30.
Good amount.
And now we can make the gearbox.
I'm making four.
Ah, wait.
This is too much.
That's a waste of gearboxing.
And that already spins the right way.
That's beautiful.
Wait a sec.
Hold on!
Hold the phone!
Hold on.
I see.
There we go.
Much better.
Okay, so that's going.
And andesite alloys come from...
Let me show you how those are made.
Mixing.
No heating required, but probably water.
Actually, maybe not even.
That needs andesites.
Let's have a mixer here.
I'm assuming we need a basin for that though.
Yeah, hold on.
How's that going to work?
Let's look at the mixer.
Mixer?
Did I not bring any?
What?
I must have brought them.
That's crazy.
I don't know.
Must have left them at home.
Not sure why I would do that though.
I love these windows.
Every time I come running here.
I appreciate them.
Aha!
They were hiding in that one box.
So we may need water for this.
Thank you, God.
That's what I needed.
The question I have though...
Like, we can't just mix on the belt, right?
We obviously need the basin.
There's no other way I can see this working.
So let's just remove this real quick.
Let's put the basin here.
Wait a sec.
Why did I just put it here?
Make it super simple.
Now we mix it.
Oh, right!
That needs...
Rotation that way.
Now it's getting interesting.
All right.
It's not actually that hard.
We can do it.
Oh, that doesn't even reach.
Oh, shit.
No!
In it goes.
Ah, let's see.
I think I'm just gonna use the...
I'm trying not to use the gearboxes, right?
Because they're so valuable.
But I think I may have to.
Yeah, we don't need this anymore, I guess.
Can I...
Oh, hold on.
We also have this one here.
That's a rotation right there we can utilize.
Yeah?
And we can put a big wheel.
Is there not a way to, like, angle this cock wheel on it?
So that's what we need, right?
No, it's not aligned.
Ow!
Oh, wait.
We can also come in here!
Big wheel now.
Oh, man.
Ah!
It needs to go one further out.
Then we have it.
We got it!
Oh!
It's overstressed.
What does that mean?
It means we need a new power source, maybe.
Let me try the naive solution here.
The gearboxes.
I need a vertical one.
Can I rotate that?
Nah.
Nah!
Aha!
There it is.
Even better.
Two small wheels.
Not overstressed.
Maybe I use a casing here.
Man, I think I used them all.
Oh, well.
See, here's the problem.
When this is done, it's not going to automatically jump up out of the basin and onto the belt.
That would be crazy, right?
I just can't see that happening.
Let's just try and mix it.
And see what happens.
Because who knows.
I need some strip locks, of course.
Oh, yeah.
We can strip them on this door now.
Look.
Oh, you asshole.
No, don't!
Okay, good.
Oh, nice.
Thanks.
Look at the way they're arriving.
One of these.
And one of these.
That's not...
Okay, so we probably need water.
We can bring it in with this, but let me just test.
Oh, wait.
I'm an idiot.
This is not what I'm mixing.
Oh, shit.
Wrong one.
This is andesite and diorite.
Wrong mix.
Wrong recipe.
Where's my...
toolbox there?
Diorite.
Actually, just take one.
One of each.
One.
Two.
Okay, they're mixing.
What happens?
Are they gonna jump up magically?
Abracadabra?
Huh.
Maybe it's a funnel again.
Are we funneling?
Wait a sec.
Funnel, funnel, funnel.
No.
God, I hate when that happens.
Wait, how does that even...
Huh?
Oh, wait.
The funnel can go down?
Oh, look.
There's an arrow on it.
Yo.
That's crazy.
Would you stop doing that, please?
No.
Stop.
It's ugly.
Bro.
Thank you.
Look at that.
You see it?
It's wonderful.
Wait, this is that.
Oh, this is almost too perfect to be true.
Look at the way we connect this now.
Oh.
And the way to get in, I guess we funnel again.
No.
Yes.
But, yeah, it's kind of weird now that we're...
Okay, I guess we're doing one level lower now.
Dude, I am learning so much from this session here.
This is insane.
That's gonna go wrong.
So, how about we do...
Do I have another clutch?
No, not clutch.
What's it called?
Whatever that is.
Gearshift.
Also, I don't need all these belts on me.
Let's keep it simple.
Eh, good enough.
Now we rot here.
No.
Oh, wait.
It was already correct.
Great.
Hey, there we go.
And now I remove that.
Sick.
Okay.
Okay, so now we need to bring in diorite and cobblestone here.
And then we need a source of water, because that's...
Water's gonna be used up, right?
Let's actually grab some.
Diorite, cobblestone.
Okay, let me see.
I think we want a funnel again.
But can we make the funnel...
Yeah, that's actually good.
Why do you do that?
Is it because of that?
Okay, check it out.
Now we grab a chest.
Oh, no.
Get it away from me.
Desperate times need desperate measures.
That should work.
Let me see.
It's working.
That is wonderful.
But now my inventory is trash.
Again.
Oh, no.
What do I not need?
I don't need this or that.
I guess I do, but I don't right now.
Don't need this.
I really don't need the arrows.
The bed I can plop down.
And sleep, actually.
In here, we're going to put a bunch of diorite and cobblestone.
Wait, is there a maximum capacity on the basin?
No!
Wait, what the fuck?
Maybe I need to...
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
I think I know what to do.
I know what to do.
We need the output from that, which is andesite.
Come here.
Can I grab it?
Ah, shit.
Ah!
That hurts.
Andesite.
No.
Of all the times, now I can't...
Filter!
There's no filter on that?
Wait.
Show me.
What is even happening?
Yes.
Okay.
Got it.
Faster.
Placed while sneaking, it puts...
Okay, yeah.
Using a wrench, the funnel can be flipped after placement.
Yeah.
Same rules will apply for most orientations.
Funnels on belts will extract insert, depending on its movement direction.
Yes.
Okay.
Funnels should also interact nicely with a handful of other components.
Right.
Okay.
Oh!
Redstone power will prevent any funnel from acting...
Okay, so arresting it.
Cannot even...
Cannot ever...
What did that say?
Cannot ever transfer between closed inventories directly.
Shoots or smart shoots might be more suitable.
Wait, I need a smart shoot.
I need a smart system.
This right now is dumb.
It's a dumb pipe.
Okay.
Wait, brass...
What did I just read?
Oh, wait.
Brass can extract a whole stack.
Okay, that is...
I thought it was, like, just visual.
What did that say?
The value panel allows for precise control over the extracted stack side.
Hold on.
Is there a value panel on the andesite one?
Huh.
Maybe it's...
Hmm.
Oh, this is a mystery.
What if we were to take a look at...
The basin itself, huh?
Or maybe the mixer.
Let's see what that says.
Oh!
With a mixer and basin some...
Oh, this looks way more sophisticated.
I like this.
How did you do that?
Okay.
Oh.
Yeah.
It's getting mixed.
But why is it not falling out before mixing?
Available recipes include any shapeless crafting recipe plus a couple extra ones.
Meaning recipes where it doesn't matter which order you make it like on the crafting table.
Some of those recipes may require the heat of a blaze burner.
Wait, how did you make that thing in the start?
Oh!
Wait a minute!
Ah!
Dude!
It's hidden in there!
It was hidden!
Oh, wait a sec.
Do I...
I don't even need a funnel here!
So funnel is unnecessary.
It will just work.
Why is it not mixing?
There's no diorite.
It's mixing!
But watch!
It's gonna come out now.
Ah!
There it is!
Why is there a wheel on that one?
My inventory...
Sucks, dude!
We need more chests.
I can't handle this.
Can't handle it.
Oh, it's rough.
In.
Give me this.
Almost lost my wheels.
Hoi, hoi, hoi.
Give me.
Give me!
No!
I'm too slow!
Give me.
I got it.
Woo!
We made it work!
I don't...
Yeah.
Okay.
I mean, this is...
This is good.
It's good.
Very good.
But of course, now this needs to go up here.
This was the whole problem.
Uh...
Oh!
Hold up!
Guys.
Are you ready?
I'm gonna...
No, I'm not gonna use a fan.
I'm gonna move everything.
Let's be principled here.
This is disgusting behavior.
What happened to that?
But first, I gotta fix my inventory!
I can't stand it!
It's such a blocker!
I need...
I need chests.
I need to...
Empty my crap.
And you know what?
We don't need belts.
We need...
Like...
Five belts!
That's it!
Maybe ten...
Belts.
Maybe...
Twenty belts.
Actually...
We need...
Twenty-eight belts.
Wait, is 61 the max?
There's no way that's...
Huh?
61?
What happened to 64?
The hell is that logic?
That makes no sense to me at all.
That is so arbitrary.
Okay, whatever.
Uh, shoots.
Hand cranks.
Trap doors we don't need anymore.
Get rid of them.
We don't need this contraption.
We don't.
We don't need all these, but...
They're stacked, so it's fine.
Buckets.
We only need one of those, actually.
Okay, uh, wood.
Don't need it.
The alloy we do kinda need.
Let's bring some chests now.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Maybe...
Everything.
We're gonna have a chest with chests in them.
The rest is good, I think.
Hand crank is...
Yeah, it's needed.
We need that.
Fluid pipes?
Maybe we make some more, because I actually need that soon.
A smart fluid pipe.
I guess for certain liquids.
Copper and sheets.
Okay.
Oh my god, I got it.
We can make tons of this.
28.
No problem.
I think I'm happy.
It's my dad.
He always texts me at this time, when he knows I'm doing this.
Yeah, this is looking good, actually.
The only problem now is...
I need to move this a little to the right.
There to here.
And maybe I'll do the thing where...
I come from a higher elevation?
I mean...
Let's get rid of this first.
Yeah.
There we go.
Now, I got rid of some stuff, didn't I?
All my dirt is gone.
Shit.
Gimme.
First things first.
Don't need this anymore.
Thank you.
Now we use pipes.
I mean, these.
Here.
And that now needs to go...
Well, I guess here.
And that's already rotating, which is wonderful.
That's gonna go in there.
This goes away.
Because now I wanna come in from this side...
And shoot it out that way.
And I guess we can make it kinda smart.
Where we say...
Like that.
And look, it's gonna go straight on it.
But then we have to elevate everything a little.
Just...
Okay, I guess.
Mixer.
Hey, it even...
Look!
It's perfect.
Ha-ha!
Not bad.
And now we gotta go into that with a funnel.
Can we actually make turns with the belt?
I guess we just have to push it onto another belt at a corner.
Yeah.
Okay.
I need more dirt.
The belt revolution is real.
That goes in there.
And here's the thing.
I, uh...
I guess I would just have to manually fill up chests with...
Diorite.
And cobblestone.
We could even have a belt...
That goes into the mines.
Down there.
You know, brings it back out here to bring it into a chest.
That then puts it into this mixer.
Not too shabby.
Let's just see how this is gonna rotate.
It's gonna rotate wrong.
Uh, wait.
It's not gonna work.
Getting the hang of this.
And there it goes.
Nice.
Now we have a chest at the end.
With a funnel.
Although I wonder if we can somehow...
Do that from below.
The chest is here.
Uh, not really.
Unless we maybe...
No, it's not gonna work like that.
Not that it's a problem.
Hey.
Yeah, it's getting kinda late here.
Let me sleep.
Dude, the fact that belts can actually transport me...
Let's say I were to put in, like, infinite speed.
Isn't that just like a fast travel method?
Like, obviously these are spinning slow.
But let's say they spin a thousand...
You know, rotations per second.
And I just go...
Across the screen.
I feel like there's gotta be, like, a limit to how fast you can spin those.
But it would be fun.
Here we go.
Are you ready?
It's finally happening.
That's gonna go into...
Hold up a second.
What needs to go in here is andesite alloys.
So we have andesite coming out.
Needs to be mixed with iron or zinc.
Oh, shit.
Hold up now.
Yeah, okay.
I mean, that kinda...
That works.
Now a funnel?
Looks kinda weird, though.
Doesn't it?
Don't fall down there.
Now we mix again.
Oh, we can use the same rotation for this!
We need more power.
Actually, no.
We need a separate source of power.
I wonder.
Wait a minute.
Dude.
Okay, you wanna see something perverse?
Check it out.
Uh...
I wonder if...
Hold on.
Before I can do the perverse thing.
I need to think.
Wait, is the water coming?
Oh, it is.
It is.
It's coming.
Wait, can it even reach?
Ah, we may have reached the limit here!
Or...
Need more pumps?
Okay.
Let me try and...
What does it take to make the pump?
Can I just make it?
Wow.
What if I...
Were to just add two pumps?
Let's say we make it...
Amazingly simple.
Is that just gonna work?
Oh.
Right.
It's overstressed.
Hmm.
Well, shit, guys.
We may have reached the limit with this water wheel!
Dang.
There's no such thing as a free lunch, apparently.
I didn't want to have to do this, but we're gonna have to implement...
Another source of power.
Yeah, doesn't this look amazing?
I love looking at it.
This factory is gonna be so big in time.
Right now, it's small steps, you know?
Yeah, I think I'm gonna have to...
Are there other ways?
So we have wind, and we have water.
What about fission?
Can I not do something like that?
Or burn some coal and spin, like, an engine?
Boil some water?
Let me look at my...
Ponder thing.
Kinetic sources!
Wait, this is a source?
What do you mean?
Right now, I only know of four sources...
Wait, why is this?
Valve handles can be used to rotate components by a precise...
Angle?
The angle can be configured on the input panel?
Why would you like to do this?
Right click to activate one rotation.
Sneak right click to activate in the...
Okay, okay, whatever.
Color it.
Got it.
Not what I need.
I need to boil some water, man!
That has to be possible.
Like, there's just no way that's not possible.
I need to discover something I haven't found yet.
Maybe if I just naively put...
Flame to...
Water?
Is it that simple?
Oh.
Wait.
Actually, yeah.
Let me try.
Bucket.
Lava, you come with me.
Now we get water.
This is the most naive approach, but I just want to see.
Okay, let's say I were to boil water...
And create steam, right?
It would have to drive like a wheel.
Or something, of course.
Or even better, a magneto.
And we can generate electricity.
I don't think this is working.
Even though there's like a visual effect on it.
Give me the lava.
Lava is valuable.
Okay.
Let me see here.
I mean, I could just make a windmill, but...
Let me just review everything.
What about this one?
Mechanical crafter.
Brass casing crafting table.
I can try to make that.
That's new.
I can't not see this as a telephone.
I bet something happens if I make this.
Meaning I unlock something new, you know?
Steam engine!
Literally on my cursor!
Oh, but is that going to be for train?
Let's find out.
Golden sheet, alloy, and copper.
I may not have enough copper for this.
Wait, I do.
In fact, we go blast.
We go blast right now.
There, gimme.
Put this...
Uh...
There.
Blast!
I'm making a little rotten meat stew over here.
Don't worry about it.
Back in.
Come on!
I'm gonna be fast.
Hey!
Oh, that was almost like a millisecond.
You can count it.
It was a millisecond.
Now.
Put this back before we hurt ourselves.
And...
Burn this damn meat!
Thank you.
Now we needed, uh...
This.
And...
Oh, I needed to make blocks out of that.
Copper.
Just one, right?
Actually.
Steam?
Wait, there's a bunch of steam shit!
Steam vent!
What?
Dude.
We're making multiple things.
Are you kidding me?
Steam engine?
Got it!
Dude, let's ponder on that.
Oh!
Let's see!
Steam engines can be placed on a fluid tank.
Nice!
Why are there little pictures, though?
Clicking the engine with a shaft creates the kinetic output.
Okay.
Oh my god, it's gonna totally rotate that.
It's gonna go in and out, in and out, in and out.
Bit of the old in and out action.
With sufficient heat, water, and boiler space!
Yo, what?
Dude, this is insane!
You wanna know something?
When I was like, oh, I need to make steam before, you know?
I was honestly just sort of...
wishful thinking, you know what I mean?
Like, oh, I wish I could do that, you know?
That would be so cool.
You can actually do it!
I had no hopes at all!
That that would be a real thing.
I was just thinking out loud, you know?
The minimal setup requires four fluid tanks.
Okay.
Oh, blaze burners?
Add wood to it.
With the help of blaze burners, the power output can be increased.
Okay!
Very nice!
And look at that, it's sucking up water!
Why do we do this, though?
What's this for?
That's a big tank.
Higher power levels require more water, size, and heat.
Nice.
Makes sense.
Why... wait, hold on.
What's the point of making a bigger tank, though?
Isn't everything you want from this simply rotational energy?
Why not just have a small tank?
I mean, you keep pumping up water anyway, right?
Makes no sense.
Higher power levels require more water.
The boiler's current power level can be inspected with engineer's goggles.
Oh, okay, so more water...
Ah, okay, I see.
I see.
That's why you want to make it big.
The more water...
Oh my god!
With each added power level, an additional engine can output at full capacity!
That is insane!
And this is about stress levels, I guess.
Level 4.
What?
4 engines.
Oh!
Okay!
Dude, what?
Level 8!
Wait, those are blue!
This looks absolutely incredible.
I love this animation.
Wait, am I hearing a frog?
You hear that?
She's going like...
In the left ear.
Listen to the frog!
What the fuck is that?
Is it the song?
That's weird, man.
I can't believe I can actually do this.
Oh my god.
We...
Oh, dude.
We even have...
We have a water place!
We...
We're sucking up water already!
What about the steam vent?
Golden sheet.
Vent.
Oh, I'm going to ponder on that.
Looks like a little mouth.
Steam vents generate lift by filling balloons with steam.
No way.
So we go fly.
When powered with redstone, the steam vent will gradually fill the balloon above itself.
Dude, that is actually amazing.
Like steam engines, sufficient heat, water, and boiler space are required.
Oh.
Ha!
Alright.
Wait, what is that thing back there?
What the hell is that?
That looks like some kind of engine.
The input panel can be used to select the maximum steam output.
Adjusting the redstone input will scale the selected output proportionally.
Whatever you say.
Dude, I don't care about this right now.
That comes later.
I am intrigued by the freaking...
Uh, the boiler one.
I want to make that now.
Don't need this.
This is what we need.
This looked like a cuckoo clock to me.
Like a little cuckoo, you know, with a little house on top.
Call me crazy.
Doesn't that look like it?
Look.
Looks like it.
Okay.
Uh, then we needed...
We needed the tanks.
Barrels.
Okay, barrels.
Uh...
Oh no, not the slabs.
Good thing I have them already.
Give me three, because I already have one.
Look at that.
Blew a tank.
Okay.
Two sheets.
Four fluid tanks?
That means...
One steam engine.
Let me just see what else I needed real quick.
The pump we have.
I don't understand this back there.
What is the point?
Oh, let's make these...
Campfires.
Coal, sticks, and wood.
We have it, I think.
Oh, it's oak.
Logs.
Need one more.
I actually have it here.
Oh, it's sticks that I'm missing.
There we go.
That's it, right?
We got the tank.
We got the water coming in.
We got this.
That's rotation, baby.
It is actually perfect.
I can't believe we went into the steam age already.
This was the last thing I expected to happen today.
Thought it was a creeper.
Okay, obviously this is bad.
We don't like this.
Is the water reached now?
Oh, wait.
We also have another one here that we don't need.
Yep.
Okay.
Oh, yes!
But actually...
We're gonna put it a little further back.
Also, I don't like that this is not covered.
Really should fix that.
Yeah, let's go excavate.
We need to excavate anyway.
Make room for the factory.
One thing you could do, actually, is just make a digging machine...
...that is like this wide and just go...
...that way.
Oh.
How do I always end up with an inventory that is unmanageable?
I can fill it up with everything.
And we come grab what we need when we need it.
I had enough.
I just got immense satisfaction out of emptying my inventory just now.
Just putting everything in there was cathartic.
Okay.
I should do it.
I think I want to put the tank...
...uh...
...a little further back.
But let's fill this hole.
That's why I was here.
So how do I actually get down there and crawl?
Maybe if I...
I have no idea.
There it is.
Nice.
I don't like all these bends in the pipe.
The pipe pens are bad.
What if we put the water in...
...from the bottom?
Can it be done?
Let's see.
Need a tank.
It can be done!
That's even more elegant.
We are actually making piping under the ground.
Just like real life.
Isn't that kind of amazing?
This is it, right here, under my bed.
That way I can be nice and hot during the night.
Is it gonna reach?
It's gonna reach.
Fantastic.
Ah, but hold on, hold on, hold on!
We need to heat it!
Shit!
I didn't think of that.
That works.
I'm happy.
And it kind of looks cool the way it comes up like that.
I actually dig it.
Yep.
Maybe even...
I kind of want to put a cover on that somehow.
Isn't that something you can do?
Just like the andeside stuff.
Alrighty.
Now that we have done that, watch this.
Wait, what?
Ah!
Right.
Okay.
There it is.
Can I rotate that?
By chance.
Oh my god, I can even...
Sick.
I meant more like, um...
90 degrees, so...
The rotation goes...
Whatever.
That's fine.
Maybe there's a way to do that.
No.
Okay.
Now...
Uh...
The pump is gonna pump water in here, so this is now full.
Except...
Why can't I see any windows inside?
I guess I just can't.
Let's turn on the temperature.
Oh yeah.
It's spinning!
Heheheheh, dude!
Oh yeah.
We have finally done it.
It's kinda slow though, but...
Okay.
I like the psss sound.
It's very satisfying.
Now we have an extra source of power.
Man, I wish I could rotate this 90 degrees.
In fact, hold on.
Wasn't it rotated in the drawing?
Uh...
Sources.
Here we go.
Let's see.
Yeah!
Look!
It's rotated in the damn drawing, dude!
It is possible!
How?
How do I do it?
Ah,
there we go!
Very nice!
Alright!
Uh...
I guess we bring this over to that spot.
I mean, this is not great looking.
I get it.
It is bad.
Now I need some wheels.
Maybe also some gearboxes.
Would be nice.
Let me think.
Up!
Yeah, up.
That's gonna be annoying.
Hmm.
In fact, why don't we just...
Nah, let's keep it simple.
Gearbox.
Just to be the vertical variety.
Like that.
Another vertical.
That's impossible.
And now we have to rotate that.
Nice.
Except it's wrong.
Kill!
Ah!
Ew!
I hate this look!
Maybe we can pretty it up later.
You know?
Right now it's definitely not the greatest.
In fact, hold on.
This is way too slow anyway.
Let's actually speed this up a bit.
Some gear reductions.
What was I thinking?
Oops.
Wrong.
Wait, what am I even doing here?
That's wrong.
No, that is correct.
That is correct.
What the...
Wait, what am I doing here?
There we go.
No, what?
Dude, I already forgot how to do this.
That spins that.
Small.
Big, right?
I'm doing it the opposite way.
It's weird that this works through the floor.
Now a big one.
I can't put it here, right?
Let's go.
Yeah.
Okay.
See how fast that is.
Damn.
It may actually be too fast.
This could be a problem.
But the problem is...
Big wheel...
Actually, this works.
It's not pretty, but...
Oh no!
It's the other way!
I thought I had it.
Dang.
And then I need a gearbox...
Vertical.
Oh, I have to be on top of it.
Fine.
I'll...
It's still wrong.
What is wrong with me?
I don't want to use a million small gears, dude.
But I will do it!
I don't give a shit!
Look at that spinny-roo!
It be spinning!
I mean...
You know.
It works.
Obviously, we're not going to do that.
That's freaking disgusting.
And I am...
I am disgusted with myself.
I am.
I really am.
Hey, wait a sec!
Why don't I just do this?
I actually had it before.
No.
Oh my god, dude.
I had it!
Much better.
It'll have to do.
I can't get over that.
Yeah.
Okay.
Let's sleep.
There's no monsters here, even though there's no light.
I guess they're just afraid of the...
Of the industrialization that's happening in this part of the world.
They don't want no part of this.
The good news is...
Yo.
Yo!
Watch this!
We have power from this side now!
What?
Oh, it...
Oh, right.
Damn.
Damn!
Never mind.
Thought I was all cool and shit.
But I wasn't.
Okay.
All of that just to not have it overstress over here.
But hey!
We learned a lot in the process.
We can now make steam.
And it's actually weirdly effective.
It's an infinite source, too.
It's kind of...
Perverse that...
I use...
The water movement here...
To generate...
A little basin of water that I then suck up.
And I suck it up with the same...
Motion of the wheel.
And then I use this water to generate even more motion.
It's kind of messed up.
I'm kind of triple dipping on this water.
Nice.
I cannot stop just looking at it, you know?
Especially with the little psst in the background now.
What about the train whistle?
I need to make this thing go...
You know?
When the steam goes.
I want to hear that.
That would make me happy.
Like a proper factory noise.
Anyway, I think we are almost at the point now where we can do this.
So inside of here, we are going to mix...
What was it?
Andesite is going to come out.
No.
Andesite is going to come in here.
Right?
And it's going to be mixed with...
No, no, andesite in here with the iron stuff.
And iron is going to come from...
Dude, I fucking forgot.
Andesite!
Let's see.
Alloy is the one that gets pushed onto the hand.
So we need andesite and iron nuggets.
Right?
So iron nuggets are going to come in from a random source.
I don't know.
It's just maybe a chest.
But andesite is going to get mixed.
And that mix happens here.
And then in this one...
It's going to get mixed again, but with the nuggets.
So we need another input...
That is going in here.
Which means we need another funnel.
No!
Stop it!
There.
Or maybe even better...
Let's put a chest in front of it.
Yeah, that's easier.
What the...
Stop that.
Okay, wait.
Why are you not...
Can I not just transfer directly?
Or...
Oh, shit.
Well, I didn't think of this.
Do I really need another build?
I don't want to.
It's such a hassle to set up here.
Oh, man.
Really?
What about the...
You know...
Diagonal.
Where is it?
Shoot!
And then...
We're going to have to do this.
What?
No.
That's not going in there, is it?
Wait, where did it go?
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
I have an idea.
It's so simple.
It's disgustingly simple.
That's it.
Ha-ha!
That works.
It works.
Oh, no.
Got it.
I don't like the fact that it's not, like, centered here.
But I see the reason why it can't be, you know?
Okay.
Well.
It works.
Let's make some...
Nuggets!
I need more nuggets.
A lot of nuggets.
And then we're going to try a full production run.
Let's see here.
What do I have?
Oh, my God!
Look at all these nuggets!
What the hell?
I had so many?
Amazing.
I think we're ready to finally perform.
Now.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
I need to set, like, an output on this.
That needs to be andesite alloy.
Which I have, I think.
I have it.
There.
Wait, why is it in every direction?
Maybe it's okay.
Wait, wait, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
They're flying in the wrong...
Oh, no.
This doesn't work.
Abandon ship.
Oh, man.
Fine, I'll use a fucking belt!
God, I hate it.
I'll use a belt.
I really didn't want to, but I'm gonna.
Like that.
Okay.
Dude, there's no way this is... Can I not just fucking put a chest or something and put it in there?
Not nozzle.
Wait, hold on.
Recipe sequence.
Cut with saw.
Process and press.
Random salvage.
Dude, I need to do this.
Oh!
Wait, auger shaft!
How do I just... Oh my god.
Dude, hopper!
That works, right?
It goes horizontal.
It doesn't even need anything.
It's actually perfect.
I can't believe I forgot about the hopper.
We put it on from the side and it should just go in.
Tell me you can have multiple inputs.
No.
Oh, thank god!
I thought I couldn't do it!
Oh!
Alright, let's see.
Yeah!
That's... That's all I needed.
That's actually perfect.
Okay, so that's done.
Great.
Fill her up.
And there she blows.
Okay, now...
Uh...
Diorite.
And cobblestone.
Damn, I have a lot.
It's amazing.
Maybe I alternate like this, you know?
Oh, wait, wait!
Wait!
We need wood!
Oh, shit!
Uh...
Chest.
And then, uh...
Here.
Yep.
No.
In you gooo!
Watch this!
Oh, no.
Wait, wait.
It's not ready.
Wait, what the fuck is...
Give me that.
Wait, oh!
Wait, we don't know...
Oh, wait.
We're missing water.
Never mind.
It's all fucked.
We're done.
It's over.
It's over!
But it's raining!
Come on!
Fill up the...
Baskets!
What about rainwater?
Oh, man.
I'm sleeping.
Yeah, we need water.
I need my bucket.
Let me just see real quick.
I need to test something.
Yep.
My test is correct.
Diorite does indeed float.
I knew it was a fake stone.
Wait, why...
Why, um...
Oh, we...
Oh, sh...
I see.
It's full.
I...
Oh, no.
We need multiple inputs.
Wait, why am I not just...
Dude, Tom Holland!
Hello?
The...
Wait!
Popper!
Uh...
That's a...
I don't have a...
I don't have that much iron.
I don't have it.
I just don't have it.
Ah...
Let's go see if I have it.
I don't think I have it.
Man, what a disaster this production line is!
But it's been, you know...
Filled with lessons.
That's the important part.
Okay, let me see here.
Um...
Iron...
Oh my god, I have nothing!
You gotta be kidding me.
I thought I got a bunch when I was digging the other day.
With my machine.
Maybe we don't need it.
Belts are fine.
So we have enough for belts, I think.
Yeah, we actually have enough.
It's fine.
Maybe one more chest.
If I have it.
Don't have it.
We're gonna use belts.
Besides, hoppers are too quick!
We can't savor all the little...
Emotions.
Give me all the diorite.
Okay.
Now I wonder...
Uh...
Will you stop it?
Okay, whatever.
Just...
Do your thing.
It's okay.
Yeah.
Here comes the airplane!
Watch it go.
I need, uh...
Belts.
Oh, I like that it's waiting in line!
Look!
I thought they would be gone!
Oh, that's amazing.
That is very, very convenient.
I appreciate that.
Uh...
Chest me.
There.
Another one of...
Dude, the funnels are, like, essential.
This is already spinning correctly!
It's a miracle!
Aw!
Okay, so we...
This needs to be timed correctly, I guess.
Oh, I'll...
Also, we gotta make sure here...
Um...
What the f...
What's happening here?
Oh, my inventory's full.
Shit.
Diorite.
Diorite in here.
Stone in here.
Grab everything in there.
Diorite.
It's mixing!
Oh, wait, wait!
Uh...
Problem, problem!
Add the side!
Gimme.
I...
I got it.
I didn't...
I didn't get it.
Come on.
Gimme.
Hap!
I got it.
Boom!
There we go!
Amazing!
Eh...
Oh, wait!
We ran out of wood!
Emergency!
Fill her up!
This is so much fucking fun, dude!
Put it in.
Oh!
Raw materials!
Go brrrr!
More!
In you go, little friends!
This is amazing, dude.
I can look at this forever!
Honestly, if I owned the real factory in real life, I would also just look at the factory all day.
I'm like, this is amazing.
It's doing it all on its own.
Look at it!
Ah, we ran out of wood.
Wait, what's happening?
Wait, are we... What's happening?
Oh, it's mixing again.
Jackie, what's up, Jackie?
Come here.
Look at what daddy has made.
You see this over there?
That's the mixer.
It mixes diorite and cobblestone together.
And it's making... what?
Andeside.
That's right!
It's making andeside.
And it's coming out the other side.
Okay, you don't want to be here anymore?
Good.
It's a beaut, Clark!
Can't wait to encase it in metal and pollution.
In you go.
Oi, oi, oi.
We need to wait.
Oh!
Ah!
Saw!
Right here!
We automatically plant a tree.
We chop it.
We grab it.
We deposit it.
In automation.
Wow!
Write it down.
Next page.
No.
Make a tree chopper at the top of the mountain.
Because it is a mountain.
Because it is a mountain, if you think about it.
It all flows downhill into the last...
It's like a... It's like a potential.
You know?
Goes from high potential to low potential.
Gets converted into kinetic energy.
Oh, yeah.
Look at this.
Some of the old... Good old ultra-violence.
Now, obviously, this is ugly.
We gotta prettify all of this down the line, but this is good.
No pun intended.
Um... Also, is this... Is this being mixed proportionally?
It must be, right?
The only problem we have now is how on earth are we gonna automatically get sink ingots?
Unless we have some kind of unbelievable world destroyer machine.
And I'm talking a real big fella.
Something the size of 50 by 50.
Right?
And it's just going through the world on its own.
It's... I'm not even... I'm... Hands off, Mom.
No hands.
Look.
It's going.
It's just eating up everything.
And then somehow, someway, bringing it back.
Yeah.
In fact...
Who says...
That we have to drill horizontal?
Elevator?
With a drill at the bottom?
Holy shit, dude.
I didn't even think about that.
But, hold on.
There is an issue with that.
It may not work.
Because the reason why the drill normally works horizontally is because of the minecart.
And everything is just powered, right?
So I don't know if it works like that when there's no minecart.
So...
Ah, maybe it's not gonna work, actually.
But, there's probably a way to do it, right?
In any case, you can always go, like, diagonally down.
Yeah.
Oh, man.
What a day.
What a beautiful day!
I am the one who grabs the sun and all that.
Insert quotes left and right.
Man, oh man.
Let me go to sleep.
Can you now imagine having a factory, right?
Right here.
We're gonna encase this in brick.
And stone.
We're gonna have pipes running along the ceiling.
From one end to the other.
Underground!
Believe the floor.
Piping.
We're gonna have wheels spinning.
It's gonna be the craziest shit you've ever seen.
And from the outside, it's not gonna look like much.
Except, of course, we have exhaust pipes.
That bring out dark liquid.
And we spill it into the ocean.
We pollute the planet.
And on top of it all, we're gonna have ballerinas on pillars.
Dancing.
20 bushels!
But this time, all at once.
And we will realize it.
What do you think?
Isn't that a beautiful idea?
I think I'm onto something here.
Oh, yeah.
We're gonna be rich!
All the money shall be mine.
And you know what?
We're gonna use all this power.
To, of course, do good in the world.
We're not just gonna pollute the planet.
You know, we're gonna make sure everything is good at first.
You know, the villages love it.
They're gonna come here.
They're gonna see all the nice progress I've made.
I'm gonna give them industrialization!
Right?
But then, when they least expect it...
Rockpool!
That's right.
And shittification.
The power I provide will now be a subscription service.
You guessed it.
They're gonna hate it.
But they're gonna be dependent on it.
And I will be the rule...
The ruler...
Of the world!
I'm so evil!
It's crazy!
Man!
But...
You know, let's not let success get to our heads.
It's...
It's still small steps right now.
We can't go overboard with this.
I mean, yes, we made a working little...
Fabrication line here.
But we have to calm down, you know?
We haven't ruled the world yet.
So we should just calm down here.
Yes!
Piss for me!
Again!
Cheers!
Oh yeah!
That's beautiful.
And you know what's funny?
All of what you see here...
Is coming from this stream.
Right up there!
This water!
This water...
Is being sucked up...
By the pipe.
And the only reason the pipe works is because the water is powering the wheel!
Right?
The water is being sucked up into a little chamber.
Okay.
We cheated a little bit.
We added some heat from the fires here, so it's not just the water.
But you know.
It almost is.
And then everything is working from there.
We may actually need more power sources too.
I'm thinking maybe a windmill on top of the...
On top of the factory, right?
To provide pinpoint power sources where we need it.
Write it down.
Pin-pound power source where we need it.
I'm kidding.
Come on.
Power sources where...
We need it.
Also...
Look for...
Potential...
Other...
Sources of power.
Fission.
That's probably not in the mod.
But then again, I said the same thing about Steam.
Who knows?
Okay.
So, I guess I want to use brick for this house.
Or for this encasing.
It needs to look like a proper factory.
It cannot be wood.
It can't be normal stone.
It needs to be like...
Industrial...
You know, industrial...
Think of England.
At the end of the 19th century.
Something like that.
That's what I'm imagining.
Maybe a bunch of copper, you know?
Copper and bricks.
That's a good mix.
Let me fix my inventory here.
This is all disgusting.
That's good.
Keep the bow on me.
I guess I should keep...
Factory related stuff in this box.
So...
This is not factory related.
Actually it is.
But this is not.
So all of that comes out.
This is all factory related.
Put this in there.
21 andesite casings.
I have 43 now.
Actually, you know what?
Yes, this is the floor.
But ideally, I actually want to collect...
Just the andesite alloys at first.
Because I already have stripped wood on the floor.
So I would just go around and, you know...
Put that on there.
And then for future floors...
Then I will have more...
Funnel in there.
I guess I never used a depot.
I thought I would need them.
Turns out I don't.
Wait, I have sink nuggets?
Hey, put them in.
I even have iron nuggets too.
Those can work as well.
Belts, of course.
And we have more...
I was about to say we have more diorite, but we don't.
Lots of cobblestone though.
We gotta go dig again.
Dig for more diorite.
And...
Get more...
Wood.
And then this factory will really take off.
The crazy thing is, this is just for one item.
You know?
Just, just the floor.
That's it.
Ow, ow, ow.
I keep stepping on that.
Not bad.
Kinda wanna try and put the drills on my elevator in here now.
On the bottom of it and see if it actually is gonna spin.
Oh, can I...
I need to find a way to pause it, like...
Um...
Wait, what?
There we go.
It's paused.
Now...
We just gotta try with one.
And I think we need glue for this too.
Oh, I can...
I keep forgetting I climbed the damn rope!
That is so convenient.
No...
How
will I see?
Dude, I actually love my house.
It looks so nice.
Oh, I removed that, didn't I?
What?
Why did it stop?
Oh,
wait!
This never went with it!
Oh, I see.
Ha!
That's funny.
Climb up!
Is it...
It's spinning!
Oh, shit!
No, no, it's not gonna dig anywhere.
It's just one.
I didn't mean to jump all the way down!
Wait, is it actually...
Okay, it stopped.
Okay, well...
This now opens up possibilities.
That's kind of amazing that it still spins, and it's not on a minecart.
So I guess every single...
Oh god, stop.
Maybe every contraption that is simulated automatically provides power.
That's how the rules are.
It doesn't matter how it's done, as long as it's simulated, there's power.
That's huge.
Okay.
Yeah, let's just end there.
Right... there.
Wonderful.
Man, what a day of discoveries.
That was absolutely wild.
Wasn't it?
I feel like I learned...
10x the amount that I learned in all the other streams.
In one stream.
I'm not a tyrant.
I'm a benevolent ruler.
What did you think of my little factory?
Was it painful to watch?
Be honest.
I imagine it was, but that's fine.
I'm not offended if you think it was.
In fact, I think it's funny.
Let's switch to something more.
It's more relaxing.
It's more like it.
Man, I keep thinking about blueprints, actually.
What a game, man.
What a game.
I'm an evil factory-owning member of the bourgeois?
You betcha.
But right now we're nothing.
We're still, you know, small-scale.
We'll get there at one point.
You've healed my create experience.
Going from wanting to do things super fast to going back to just enjoying the process.
Honestly, I don't see how you could do it faster.
I mean, obviously, this is the first time I'm playing it, so you could obviously do it faster.
But what I mean is, like, you need to collect things to do things still.
It's still Minecraft, right?
You can't just immediately make all the things.
The less relaxing music is from Desert Combat mod for Battlefield 2.
Battlefield 1.
One of the goaded mods of all time.
This is a complex mod.
Like, it really takes a while to learn.
It's definitely way more dense in information and progression than vanilla Minecraft.
And that's from someone who already knows about vanilla Minecraft and all the basic stuff in Minecraft.
Your Steam Whistle impression was dead-on.
Thank you!
I thought it was, too.
Will there be a Season 4?
Yes, and I'm thinking it's gonna be either...
No, wait, actually.
I think it's gonna be you guys making a batshit crazy-ass modpack where everyone just contributes random crap to it.
And I don't know what it is until the day I play it.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
You know what I mean?
Obviously, it would have to go through some kind of check to make sure there's nothing TOS in there.
But other than that, you know?
Go nuts!
Ha ha ha ha!
I think that could be fun.
That's gonna be unplayable?
Probably, but it's gonna be fun.
That's gonna be absolute...
craziness.
And obviously, the mods would have to be compatible with each other so it doesn't break, you know, and crash and all that.
I'm probably gonna end up in there and not knowing what is even going on or what I'm supposed to do.
Like, I'm imagining...
Uh...
Is it Oscar the Tank or something?
What is it?
Uh...
The Steam Whistle Man?
What's the...
What's the kid's show called?
With the fucking train!
With the...
You know, with the face on it.
Thomas the Tank!
Yeah, that one!
Um...
Something like that, you know?
And...
And some other stuff.
I saw that someone made that for, uh...
Skyrim.
I saw a video about it once.
It was quite funny.
Ha ha ha!
Oscar the Steam Whistle Man!
Well, I was thinking...
I forgot the name.
But it was something with O, you know?
So...
Oscar, Thomas...
I was like Oscar.
And then I couldn't remember the name for train, so I was like...
The Steam Whistle!
Because I just had the Steam Whistle things.
I'm terrible at, uh...
Recalling certain things nowadays.
I don't know, man.
Maybe I'm actually suffering from...
Old age!
My recall is not what it once was.
Well done teaching Jackie to yap.
Thank you!
I mean, she's been yapping for a while.
It's just, uh...
Unintelligible.
Like, she...
She will sing, you know?
From the other room you can just hear...
Sometimes.
And she's shy about it, too.
Like, if I then...
Get up from the chair...
She can immediately hear that I get up from the chair.
And she stops singing.
Because she knows I'm coming out there, you know?
I've yet to actually see her do it.
I can only hear her.
I think she's embarrassed.
She's saying, feed me, feed me?
I don't think so.
Because it happens at any time of the day.
She just wants your attention?
I don't think so.
Because she's playing with herself, it seems.
She's not coming in here to sing at me or scream at me.
She's just in the other room doing her own thing.
And usually it'll be followed by her running fast, you know?
So she'll go...
And then she'll...
You can just hear her sprint across the room.
And then a little later...
And then she sprints across the other side.
Yeah.
Bad sentence structure?
What do you mean?
With herself or by herself?
Oh.
How do you say that when she's just...
You know, she's just playing...
With nobody else except herself.
Because in Danish we say...
You know?
Which means playing with yourself.
But I see how that sounds wrong.
But you know what I mean.
By herself.
Oh, okay, right.
Okay, sorry.
That makes sense.
Actually sounds right too, now that I hear it.
But what if she literally had a clone of her in there...
And she was playing catch with herself?
How do you explain that?
Checkmate, atheists.
No, no, no.
Not with her clone.
It's literally her.
She's playing with her clone?
I don't know.
What's the next horror game?
Uh...
That's a good question.
I don't know.
Maybe it's gonna be...
Alien Isolation.
I would say there's a high chance of that one being the next.
When do you decide to start a new game?
When does anyone decide to start a new game?
It's really just when I feel like it.
Which is a super nice position to be in.
But that's just how it is.
And the thing is, I could be playing more games at any given time, but...
It wouldn't be fun to watch, I don't think.
Because I wanna really enjoy it, you know, and be all in with it.
I'm still deciding what to play, uh...
For YouTube right now.
So not streaming.
I feel like you left the create tutorial today.
Yeah, maybe.
That's a long tutorial.
I've heard about Dwarf Fortress, actually, Elevi.
Uh, it's not a horror game, though.
Never did I experience greater horror than when trying to understand what the fuck is happening.
Yeah, I heard it's quite complex.
But they also, uh...
The two guys that made it...
They apparently released a modern version of it, with like...
At least, you know...
Decent graphics now, so it's a lot more...
Uh... palatable, I guess.
For normal people.
It's not as...
Spreadsheety.
Is the new apartment heatwave proof?
For next week.
Wait, is the heatwave next week?
No, wait.
Really?
Let me check the weather.
Maybe Denmark will be...
Saved.
Or spared.
It doesn't look that bad here.
Okay, maybe 26, 28 degrees.
Nah, it'll be fine.
I have an AC.
It's in my...
Living room.
Definitely helps still.
But like I mentioned last time, I'm considering getting...
Some fiber optic display port cables and USB cables.
So I can route my computer into my living room, so I don't have to...
Absorb the heat...
From it, inside this room that I'm in.
Because it is technically a space heater.
You know?
With like 500 watts plus.
What kind of AC?
It's a split AC called...
Mydea Porta Split.
Here.
I'm gonna write it.
Quite expensive, but man, did it change my life.
It is worth all the money.
But that's also coming from someone who is not familiar with ACs or what they do.
For your life.
Quality.
And now I know.
I've seen the light, man.
During summer months, ACs are...
Damn, it's so good.
I can't even imagine not having an AC now.
I can't believe I've lived my whole life without it.
What are your thoughts on what to play for YouTube?
Uh...
Right now, I am...
Thinking...
I've thought about a couple games.
Let me actually pull up my backlog, so I can remember what I thought.
Uh...
Oh, by the way.
Backlog.
Here.
If you wanna see it.
Um...
I was thinking of...
One of them was the game...
Oh, God.
Why can't I remember the name of it now?
Nier Replicant.
Which is like, kind of an anime-type game, I guess.
It's a little bit weird.
But I thought, why not give it a chance?
Then I thought about Bioshock.
And...
What else?
Talos Principle 2 was definitely also a consideration.
Let me see what else I thought of.
Planescape Torment.
But maybe not this time.
Maybe later.
Shadow of the Colossus.
Pacific Drive.
They Are Billions.
Stuff like that.
But I haven't decided yet.
Maybe I'll let you guys vote on it.
And I definitely didn't mention all the games.
I just can't remember right now.
Will you play Vintage Story?
Yeah, when it's done.
It's not done, right?
It's an alpha or whatever.
Early access?
I'm not gonna go to Gamescom.
I'm like a...
I'm like a hermit, guys.
Like, I almost never go out.
I'm not a very social person.
I don't...
I don't like to...
I like being...
I'm a homebody, you know?
I like to sit at home.
Kind of would recommend playing System Shock before Bioshock.
Are they related?
Isn't System Shock like...
I don't even know.
Are they related?
At least touch grass.
I do sometimes.
Sometimes I take a break, you know, from...
Streaming entirely for like a week.
Where I go out and I hang out with friends and I actually touch grass.
Because I'm like weird in that way where...
I can totally be on my own without any social connections.
Or, you know, hanging out for months at a time.
And then out of nowhere, I'll be like...
Damn, now I really feel lonely again.
Now I need to be social.
Then I go out and be really social for a bit.
And then I'm like...
Okay, I've had enough.
Time to go home.
And lock myself in, you know?
You're lying?
About what?
I'm not lying.
How do you still have friends?
Well...
My friends are the same.
A lot of them at least.
We also get tired of each other.
And a lot of friends I just talk to online, you know?
Like, we sit on Discord or something.
Sunko from Avatar.
That sounds amazing.
Like, buying a house in the countryside sounds like a dream.
Good plan.
I've not played Viewfinder, but it's on my list.
But yeah, I gotta be honest.
I'm not the best friend if you're, like, a high maintenance person, you know?
I am terrible at...
You know...
Writing...
Like, engaging in, like, suggesting something to do.
Like, you can just leave me in a little cave and I'll be by myself for eons, you know?
But it's like...
It's nothing personal.
And I think my friends know that.
How did you discover Steam Engine?
I was on a phone call for an hour.
It's kind of funny, actually.
I was daydreaming about the idea of a Steam Engine in the game.
And then I literally opened my...
Recipe book.
Almost exactly on the Steam Engine.
With my mouse cursor on it.
And I didn't notice at first.
And then I looked at it like...
Steam Engine!
That's how it happened.
It's amazing.
It's a little more...
There's more steps than that, but...
That's pretty much it in a nutshell.
What's the music from the start of the stream?
It's from Desert Combat.
It's a mod for...
Battlefield 1.
Great mod.
Nowadays kinda dated, I guess.
But boy was that...
Something else.
I'll probably take a break before I start playing something like Factorio after something like this.
Well, Bajlash, I already did move out of Copenhagen.
Living there is like, for the ultra-mega rich.
It's so expensive to live in Copenhagen.
Now I live...
Practically on the countryside.
Not really, it's like a little town, but...
Factorio is a 40-hour game!
Yeah, right!
Dude, there's no way I would spend 40 hours in that game.
I would spend at least...
Five times that.
Because I've played it a little before.
I know what it is.
You can't...
You can't mess with me.
I'm not falling for that.
Sounds like he moved to Malmur.
Dude, I don't wanna move there.
Because now I'm suddenly in Sweden, and there's probably a bunch of new rules that I have to get accustomed to.
And then traveling back to Copenhagen is gonna be a pain...
Not that much of a pain, but kind of a pain.
Ah, I'll stay here.
Without sounding too nationalistic, man, I love my country.
I do, I love living here.
It's a good place.
As we say here, outside good, but inside best.
Actually more like...
Traveling good, but home best.
That's how I feel.
You feel like French people exist?
Yes.
But I mean, I've never seen one.
No, I'm kidding, I have.
They're real.
And they're quite nice.
The ones I've met at least.
I will not wear wigs.
If I ever lose hair, and I start to, you know, become bald, I'm taking it all off.
I'm going bald.
All the way.
There's no hesitation.
I'm ready with the scissors.
I don't care how I'm going to look, I'm going to do it.
Baldiver, exactly.
Sounds like Baldiver.
That sounds horrible.
Yeah, I would post in Bald for sure.
And I would let the council decide what to do.
I am aware of that whole thing, okay?
That's vaguely what I was kind of thinking about when I said it.
Only bald on top is peak.
The thing is though, isn't it a lot of maintenance?
Don't you have to shave that every single day to have it look sort of good?
But I guess if you're sitting inside all day every day, not meeting people, it doesn't matter.
You can let it grow a bit and then you would take it off once in a while.
But if you have a job where you go in every day and you want to look decent, you know, you want to shave it every day.
There's a mod for Create that adds meth production.
Of course there is.
I'm not surprised.
That is the least surprising thing.
Meth on belts.
I mean...
I guess that's how we make them in real life too.
That's gotta be like an assembly line for meth.
Like medicinal meth, right?
At least I'm pretty sure that's a thing.
Schedule 1, it actually sounds kind of fun.
But that's also not done, right?
Like it's being developed right now.
But I have had my eyes on it.
It looks fun.
I briefly saw Charlie play some of it from...
God, what...
Penguin Zero, you know?
The guy with the black hair and the white t-shirt.
You know who I'm talking about.
Everyone knows him.
And it looked kind of fun.
He was driving around on a skateboard...
Trading wheat with people.
You never play Early Access?
Very rarely I will.
But I just don't feel the need to it.
Like I have the patience of a saint when it comes to that.
Even games that are released that I'm excited about.
I tend to wait with those as well.
Simply because...
They're getting patched, you know?
And the more you wait...
One, the cheaper the game gets.
And the more patched it is, the better it is to play when you finally get to it.
It's like a game of the year experience at that point, you know?
With every DLC and all that stuff.
But I know...
I mean, I didn't used to be like this.
Earlier on in my life, I was definitely more like...
Oh, give me immediately, you know?
When a new Battlefield would come out that would be like a demo for it...
Or a multiplayer test or whatever...
I was always in.
Nowadays, I'm not too excited about that.
I think the latest game that I played...
That is Early Access...
Sort of...
Is Deadlock.
I love Deadlock.
But I played it a long time ago.
Apparently it's changed a lot recently.
What about Terraria blueprints?
Honestly, blueprints, in my mind, I completed.
I'm done with that game.
And I had an amazing experience.
And yes, maybe there's more, but I don't wanna...
Squeeze the lemon so hard.
It's gonna be...
It's gonna be so much potato and very little meat left for me.
I think I stopped at the perfect time.
I got my money's worth x10 out of that game, for sure.
Terraria will probably never play again.
Simply because I just don't like the game.
I know, Jackie.
I'm gonna be there this time.
Maybe you wanna...
Maybe you can sit and talk to me.
I wanna talk to them, Jackie.
Here.
Let me turn this off.
Let me also remove the gate on the microphone.
Uh, where is it?
It's kinda...
It's kinda low, I guess.
She's sitting on my lap like a human right now.
It's so funny when they do that.
Why do you sit like that, Jackie?
Oh.
Yeah, she's scratching the mic now.
I turned off the gate, but I think there's also a boost I put on the gate, so that's why it probably wasn't that loud.
Yeah, there's like 16 decibels of boost on the gate, so...
Damn.
Alright, well, guys, I'm gonna go!
Thanks for watching.
I'll see you on a stream down the road.
And new offline game coming soon.
I'll see you around.